美国DC影业
美国领域电影制作公司 联合出品
3个世纪前
最早的一批超能力生物来到地球
被称为超人类的他们 开启了神明和怪物的新时代
30年前
一个外星婴儿乘坐飞船来到地球
被堪萨斯州的农民夫妇收养
3年前
这个婴儿已经长大 他宣称自己是超人
是拥有最强力量的超人类
3周前
超人阻止了博拉维亚入侵贾汉普 在全世界引起广泛争议
3小时前
一个名叫博拉维亚之锤的超人类 在大都会袭击了超人
3分钟前
超人第一次战斗失败
噢
Ow! Oh!
停下 停下 别闹了
Stop, stop, stop.
停下
Stop. Stop.
不 小氪 小氪
No, Krypto. Krypto.
噢
Ow!
小氪
Krypto.
带我回家
Take me home.
回家
Home.
小氪
Krypto.
回家
Home.
超人
Superman!
（氪星语）我们选了这颗星球作为你的家
（氪星语）你要在那里多做好事 不要忘记氪星的真理
（氪星语）我们爱你胜过爱天空 爱你胜过爱大地
（氪星语）不久后 我们深爱的家园将要永远消失
谢谢你们
Thank you.
您没必要感谢我们 这并不会让我们感到高兴
No need to thank us, sir, as we will not appreciate it.
我们没有感情和意识
We have no consciousness whatsoever.
只是服务您的机器人
Merely automatons, here to serve.
这是12号 她是新来的
Meet Twelve. She's new.
嗨 他看我了
Hi. He looked at me.
我在播放您父母的全息录像来安慰你
I put your parents' message on to soothe you.
谢谢
Thank you.
他很喜欢这段录像
He finds it soothing.
（氪星语）我们爱你胜过爱天空
（氪星语）爱你胜过爱大地
（氪星语）不久后 我们深爱的家园将要永远消失
（氪星语）多做好事 实践氪星的真理
（氪星语）那颗星球
（氪星语）就是地球 那里的人
（氪星语）那里的人
前往地球途中 全息录像有所损坏
The message was damaged in transit from Krypton to Earth.
（氪星语）那里的人
即将开始翻译
But what is there...
（氪星语）我们爱你胜过爱天空 我们爱你胜过爱大地
我们爱你胜过爱天空
"We love you more than heaven, our son."
我们爱你胜过爱大地
"We love you more than land."
不久后 我们深爱的家园将要永远消失
"Our beloved home will soon be gone forever.
但希望点亮了我们的心 希望就是你 卡-艾尔
But hope vitalizes our hearts, and that hope is you, Kal-El."
我们选了一颗星球作为你的家 你要在那里多做好事
"We have searched the universe for a home where you can do the most good
不要忘记氪星的真理
and live out Krypton's truth.
那颗星球就是地球
That place is Earth." "That place is Earth."
录像的剩余部分已损坏
And the rest of the message is lost.
有14处骨折
Fourteen fractured bones.
受损器官有膀胱 肾脏 大肠以及肺部
Damage to bladder, kidney, large intestine, lungs.
可怜的超人
Our poor Superman.
只要接受黄太阳的照射 他很快就可以恢复活力
With a healthy dose of yellow sun, we'll have him up and at 'em in no time.
工程师 请回复
Engineer, come in.
他应该是降落在这附近
He landed somewhere near here.
我还没看到他
I can't see where.
那就好好找找
Well, keep looking.
好多了
Golly.
先生 您的体力只恢复了83% 您需要休息
Sir, you are only 83% restored to health. You must rest.
现在不能休息 我得继续战斗
No can do, Four. I gotta get back to the fray.
可这个拿锤子的家伙 不是刚刚打败您吗
But this Hammer fellow just beat you at full power.
先生
Sir?
这怎么回事
What is this?
小氪
Krypto!
你搞什么 看看我家
What the hey, dude? I-I thought--
都成狗窝了
You destroyed the whole--
超人机器人 我不是说过要看好它吗
Superman robots, I thought I told you to keep an eye on him.
我们喂它了 但它很不听话
We feed the canine, but he is unruly.
它知道我们不是有血有肉的人类
And he realizes we are not flesh and blood
在我们内心深处根本不关心它的死活
and couldn't, in our heart of hearts, care less whether he lives or dies.
行了 小氪 别闹了
Stop, Krypto, leave it.
好疼 别咬我
Ow. Ow! Stop. Ow. Stop it.
小氪 别咬了 听话
Krypto! Ow! Ow! Stop it. Stop.
待好 坐下 别动
Sit. Sit. Stay.
超人正在回去的路上
The alien is on its way back.
《超人》
你们的超人已经抛弃了你们
Your Superman has abandoned you!
博拉维亚的人们绝不会答应 超人来插手我们的边境事务
The people of Boravia will not ignore him inserting himself into our affairs.
打开所有传送门
Accelerate the portals.
他没有权力干涉
准备就绪
Primed and ready.
还有十秒 开始倒数
T-Minus ten and counting.
准备直播
Buckle up, we're going live.
是氪星人愚蠢的选择
十 九 八 七 六
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six...
二号机 遇袭的公司怎么样了
Bravo, what do you have on employees?
我看了公司内部 拉瑞 没有人员伤亡
I'm inside Chocos, Larry. No fatalities.
五 四
...five, four...
那有点遗憾哦 三 二 一
Can't win 'em all. ...three, two, one.
发现目标
Target in sight.
他回来了 五点钟方向 收到
He's back. Your 5:00. Copy.
12C
12C.
18A
18A.
34B
34B.
98Z
98Z.
8H
8H.
74D
74D.
44T
44T!
雷吉 看一下摊 好 好的
Reggie, can you watch? Yeah, yeah.
好 非常好 太棒了
Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
他好像可以提前看穿 超人的每一个动作
It's like he knows Superman's every move before he makes it.
是这样 他研究超人很多年了
He does. He's been studying him for years.
他设计了2500多个招式 应对各种情况
He's developed over 2,500 fight moves for any situation.
超人
Superman!
二号机 查到了吗
Bravo, you got him?
马里克·阿里 本地人
Malik Ali, a local.
莱克斯 工程师要通话
Lex, we have the Engineer.
我们找到了超人的冰城堡
The target has led us to the ice castle.
传言是真的
The rumors are true.
我不懂怎么会一直没人发现它
I don't know how in the hell this thing hasn't been spotted.
建筑正在下沉
（西班牙语）见鬼了
Mierda.
切换到频道一
Comms, two to one.
（西班牙语）狡猾的家伙
Hijo de...
莱克斯 整个堡垒都沉到了雪地下面
Lex, the entire structure has descended into the ice.
我知道了 你马上回来
We have what we need. Return to base.
我可以想办法进去 莱克斯
I can drill into it, Lex.
安吉拉 今天不需要你来逞能
Your pride won't be making our choices today, Angela.
谢谢 我们会带更多人过去
Thank you. We'll need more than you when we enter.
切换到频道二
Comms, one to two.
该做的都做完了 收工
We've done what we need to do. Wrap it up.
美国将永无宁日 博拉维亚之锤的愤怒火焰绝不停息
The United States will continue to feel the wrath of the Hammer of Boravia.
我不能允许那个外星人
是我 马里
It's me, Mali.
我请你吃过炸豆丸子
Once I gave you free falafel,
当时你刚救下一个女人
when you saved a woman from being hit by a taxi.
超人 你还好吗
Are you all right, Superman?
马里 你快走吧 这里不安全
Mali, you gotta get outta here. It's not safe.
你救了我们很多次 这次我来救你
You saved us so many times. Now it's our turn.
这是最后一次警告
This is your last warning.
噢
Oh!
要是你不掺和贾汉普的事儿 就不会这样
Maybe you shouldn't have done that thing in Jarhanpur, Superman.
大功告成
Flawless, people.
你们太棒了
Way to bring it home!
卢瑟集团
关闭传送门
Decelerate all portals.
超霸回来了 超霸
Ultraman's back. Ultraman!
超霸 你太厉害了
Ultraman! You did so good.
干得好
Yes!
卢瑟集团
星球日报
抱歉 对不住 借过一下
Sorry about that. I'm so sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
早啊 尼诺 早 克拉克
Morning, Nino. Good morning, Clark.
星球日报
《星球日报》博拉维亚之锤 在市区引发混乱
这些超人类又不是选举上来的
Do these unelected metahumans
居然还想要干涉我们的外交政策
think they can dictate international policy?
真是太离谱了
It's outrageous.
这是大新闻 放头版重点位置
It's a big story. Put it above the fold.
让人一眼就能看到
That's where we put it.
你又迟到了 肯特 抱歉 佩里
You're late again, Kent. Sorry, Perry.
废柴哥 嘿 史蒂夫
Hey, loser. Hey, Steve.
你能不能多用点儿生动的词
Hey, what do you got against adverbs, Kent?
让读者清清楚楚知道 你要表达什么感情
How are we supposed to know how we feel when we read this malarkey?
你听我的 修辞不够美 文章淡如水
In sports writing, you learn the sentence is the modifier.
你这也太无聊了
妈妈 妈妈
Hey, Ma. "Ma!"
克拉克
Hey, Clark!
我和你爸就想打个电话 祝贺你今天登上头版头条
Uh, me and Pa just wanted to call and say congratulations on that front page.
瞧瞧 我儿子多厉害
Boy, that is something!
问问你妈做了什么奇葩新菜
Hey, ask Ma if she barbecued up any good roadkill lately.
闭嘴 史蒂夫 什么烤负鼠 炸小肠
Shut up, Steve. Like, uh, possum or chitlins...
谁在说话 抱歉 妈
What's that, Clark? Sorry, Ma,
今天的新闻太多了
I'm just in the middle of a big news day here.
小肠能吃吗
What are chitlins?
小肠大肠都能吃
Chitlins are intestines.
谢了 凯特 你看这玩意儿了吗
Thanks, Cat. You read this crud?
写得真棒 克拉克
I thought it was great, Clark.
真棒
"Great"?
上头版了 你小子
Yeah! Front page! Big time!
好的 不多耽误你时间了 我们就是
Well, we don't want to keep you, but, uh,
想对你说声恭喜
wanted to say congrats,
我们也挺想你的 克拉克
and tell you we're thinking 'bout you, Clark.
好久不见了 跟他说 常回来看看
It's been a minute. Tell him don't be a stranger.
你爸说 常回来看看
Pa says, "Don't be a stranger."
好 我听到了
I, uh... Yeah, I heard him, Ma.
那个 行 我得先挂了
Yeah, okay I gotta go. I gotta run.
好 多保重
Yep, okay. Love you.
这个什么 博拉维亚之锤跑到市里攻击民众
So, this guy just flew into midtown and started attacking people,
就为了让超人现身
demanding for Superman to show up?
对 我的文章里都写了
Yeah. It's all there in my article.
你的意思是让我看一遍 克拉克
Then I'd actually have to make it through your writing, Clark.
我愿为真理做出许多牺牲
Knowledge is worth many sacrifices.
但这个牺牲太大了
That isn't one of them.
你真幽默 露易丝
Ha, ha, ha. Very funny, Lois.
天啊 他太帅了
Oh, my God. He's so fine.
有22个人受伤入院 财产损失超过2000万
Twenty-two people in the hospital, over 20 million in property damage.
让人不禁想问 问什么
It does make you wonder. Wonder what?
超人确实很厉害
As great as he is,
但他是不是没考虑过 博拉维亚事件的后果
maybe Superman didn't completely think through the ramifications of the Boravia thing.
那家伙都不一定是博拉维亚来的
If this guy is even from Boravia.
怎么可能 他叫"博拉维亚之锤"
What do you mean? His name is "the Hammer of Boravia."
对 可这总不可能是他的真名吧
Yeah, I doubt his parents named him that, Jimmy.
我们根本不清楚他真正的目的
We have no clue what his actual goal was here.
目的很明显吧 他要教训超人一顿
I think it's pretty obvious the goal was kicking Superman's ass.
这么说不准确 超人还没有输呢
Uh, he did-- He didn't completely kick Superman's ass.
他输得很彻底 克拉克
Pretty thoroughly, Clark.
胡扯 请你们拿出证据 证明博拉维亚和这家伙有关系
Show me! You show me what ties there are
不然 就闭上嘴
between Boravia and this "Hammer!"
古尔科斯否认博拉维亚与袭击有关
超人确实说过 博拉维亚之锤的口音似乎不是很地道
Yeah, see, Superman did say he thought the, uh, Hammer might be faking a Boravian accent.
超人真的说了吗
Superman said that?
对 我采访了他本人 他很酷
Yeah, I interviewed him right afterwards. Great guy.
说起来 真是奇怪 怎么你总能采访到超人 克拉克
You know, it's funny that you keep getting all these interviews with Superman, Clark.
没什么奇怪的 只是我太优秀而已
I don't think there's anything funny about good journalism, Lois.
呃
Uh-huh.
博拉维亚和美国之间
The relationship between Boravia
在过去的三十年中
and United States
保持着牢不可破 铁一般的结盟关系
has been like iron for 30 years,
直到 超人出来搅局
until Superman came along.
看好了 朋友们
What you're looking at, my friends,
在你们面前的是这个地球上 最强大的生物
is the most powerful being on Planet Earth:
超霸
Ultraman.
杜普瑞化工运输
是你创造了他
You created this man?
您看这个 工程师
Ooh. Check this out. The Engineer.
她当过特种兵
A former special operative,
而现在我往她的血液里 植入了无数的纳米机器人
whose blood I infused with microscopic machines called "nanites,"
她可以用机器人随意变出 任何机械
which she can form into anything she can imagine.
当然了 还有我的精英武装飞行力量 天爪小队
And, of course, you're familiar with my flying armored forces, the Raptors.
组合在一起 就是一个超强战团 叫做星球守卫者
All together, they're an unstoppable force we call PlanetWatch.
卢瑟先生
星球守卫者
他们有能力消除一切来自外星的威胁
More than capable of containing any otherworldly threat.
这么说你想让国防部
So you want the Defense Department
莫利部长雇佣这些超人类 去搞定那个氪星人
to hire your metahumans to take down the Kryptonian?
鉴于超人最近 暴力袭击了美国的盟友
After Superman acted with violence against our Boravian allies,
我想这个方案值得考虑
I think it'd be worth considering.
大超阻止了战争
Big Blue stopped a war.
弗莱格将军
他很天真 但他是好心
Naive, maybe, but well-intentioned.
可是一条失控的消防水管
Well, I don't know the intentions
真的能用来救火吗 弗莱格将军
of an unattended firehose, General Flag.
我只会当心让水别溅到我身上
I just do what I can not to be splashed.
卢瑟先生 亲切和蔼的克劳利主任
Mr. Luthor... The disarming Director Crawley.
过去两年中 博拉维亚已经向你们卢瑟集团
The country of Boravia has purchased over 80 billion dollars' worth of arms
购买了总价超过800亿美元的武器
from LuthorCorp in the past two years.
所以呢
And?
所以如果博拉维亚和贾汉普开战 获利最大的就是你
And no one would profit more from a war with Boravia and Jarhanpur than you.
让我猜猜 有了超人在中间碍事 生意就不好做了 对吗
A cynic might say that having Superman out of the way might not be bad for business.
等地球人死光了 生意才是真不好做
Well, what's particularly bad for business is dying.
要是继续放任氪星人胡作非为
And I have a distinct feeling that's where we're all headed
我看离这一天也就不远了
with the Kryptonian running wild.
你的意思是 要囚禁所有超人类
So we're gonna lock up all metahumans now?
其他超人类不会像他那样
Look, other metahumans aren't going off half-cocked,
脑子一热就去干涉外交事务
interfering in foreign affairs.
他们也没有擅自 我已经有证据了
They don't have-- And I have proof of this--
超人在南极造了一个秘密堡垒
a hidden headquarters in Antarctica
起码违反了12条国际条约
that violates 12 international treaties.
而且他们不是外星人
And they aren't aliens.
有这些理由 难道还不够
Shouldn't all that be more than enough reason
让星球守卫者行动起来吗
for PlanetWatch to at least
至少把超人带回来问个话吧
bring the Kryptonian in for questioning?
说实话我也不愿意
Admittedly, I'm not comfortable
让一个具有如此高危险性的外星生物 到处活动
with a being from another planet as dangerous as him on the loose.
可舆论怎么办 超人很受欢迎的
But the optics? Superman is popular.
我看网上的评论 他的人气越来越低了
Less so every day, according to chatter online.
泰勒司法部长
万一你们没能制服他 风险会更高
Not to mention the potential risk of failing to contain him.
我向您保证 部长 一定能制服他
I assure you, Secretary, we can contain him.
对 他们有杀手锏
Yeah, they got this stuff, uh...
叫氪石还是什么的
What's this Kryptonite stuff called?
就是叫氪石 这东西能杀掉他
It's called Kryptonite. Well, it kills him, right?
据我所知 地球上已经没有氪石了
As far as we can ascertain, there's none left on the planet.
关于这一点 我也有办法
I have a workaround for that as well.
这些都无关紧要 莱克斯
You know what? It doesn't matter, Lex.
国防部不会行动 除非你能证明超人图谋不轨
Because without solid proof of malicious intent, it's just not worth the risk.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
三个月前我们第一次约会
Three months ago, we had our first date.
所以呢 为了庆祝 我正在做你最爱吃的
And so, to celebrate, I am making you your favorite:
早餐 当晚餐
breakfast for dinner.
那是你最爱吃的
That's your favorite.
你喜欢早餐
You love breakfast.
对 我喜欢早上吃 是你喜欢晚上吃
Yeah, for breakfast. You love it for dinner.
怎么了 今天你真逗
What? It was very funny today.
什么 你在办公室跟我抬杠 太搞笑了
What? It was hilarious, the little back-and-forth we had going.
嗯
Mm.
说我文章写得不行
You giving me guff for my article.
吉米还信了
Jimmy was eating it up.
我说的是真心话 克拉克
I wasn't acting, Clark.
你总是这样采访自己 早晚有一天别人会发现的
If you keep interviewing yourself, eventually people are gonna figure it out.
可我有眼镜
But the glasses.
戴个眼镜也瞒不了多久的
Yeah, they won't fool everyone forever.
而且 你这样自问自答 其实也很不合理
And ethically, these interviews are hugely problematic.
你提前就知道要回答什么问题
I mean, y-you literally know the questions in advance.
那你来采访我
Okay, so I'll let you interview me.
那你就要更不高兴了
I'm pretty sure you wouldn't like that.
不会的 我很有媒体经验
Come on, Lois. I'm media savvy.
你问什么问题我都能应对
I can handle any question that comes my way.
你这话是认真的吗
Are you being serious right now?
是啊
Yeah.
你愿意作为超人接受我采访
You'd let me interview you as Superman?
当然
Sure.
那来吧
How about now?
呃
Um...
正在录音
好了吗
Ready?
来吧 大记者
Let's do it, Cronkite.
超人
Superman.
莱恩小姐
Miss Lane.
最近 你受到了很多批评和质疑
Recently, you've come under a lot of fire for what some might--
也没有很多吧 我
I don't know if it's a lot of fire, but--
的确有很多
It's a lot.
今天国防部长还说 会调查你在博拉维亚的行动
Today the Secretary of Defense said he was gonna look into your actions in Boravia.
这很好笑吗
That-- That's funny?
也不是真的好笑 只是
It's not "funny" funny, it's just, um...
我的行为是公开的 我阻止了战争
I mean, come on. My actions? I stopped a war.
也许吧 不是也许 是真的
Maybe. Uh, not "maybe." I did.
好吧 怎么阻止的
Okay. How?
是这样 博拉维亚要攻打贾汉普
Well, Boravia invaded Jarhanpur,
而我去告诉他们这样做不对
and I showed up and told them that wasn't right.
然后呢
And?
然后 我砸烂了几辆坦克 几架飞机还有一些别的
And... smashed some tanks and things and a couple of planes and some other stuff.
没有重大伤亡 只有人受轻伤
There were no casualties and no significant injuries.
你是不是还接触了博拉维亚总统 瓦西尔·古尔科斯
Did you interact at all with the President of Boravia, Vasil Ghurkos?
接触了一点点
A very small amount.
一点点是多少
What's a very small amount?
我跟你说过
That was between us.
这可是正式采访
This is all on the record.
对 可是博拉维亚总统的事 我已经告诉过你了
Yeah, but that conversation was between the two of us.
对 但即便我知道答案 我还是要问你这个问题
Yeah, and I would ask that question whether or not I knew the answer to it.
真的吗 真的
Really? Really.
成功阻止战争之后
After I stopped the war,
我去找了古尔科斯
I went to see Ghurkos.
在哪儿
Where?
在首都卢切贝克的王宫里
In the capital of Luchebic, at the Royal Palace.
然后呢
And?
我要求古尔科斯总统单独会见我
And I took a private audience with Ghurkos.
怎么会见
How?
我带着他飞到了沙漠里 然后
I flew him out to the desert, and I...
请继续
And you...
把他放到了一株仙人掌上
And I placed him against a cactus.
仙人掌
A cactus?
你是在 折磨他
So... torture?
不 不是折磨
No. Not torture.
刺儿都小小的 不会很扎
Its spikes were like... not even that big.
你们说了什么
What did you say?
我告诉他 要是再找贾汉普的麻烦
I told him that if he ever messes with Jarhanpur again,
他就得给我个人一个交待
he'll have to personally answer to me.
这话什么意思
What did you mean by that?
意思是如果再出事
That if such events occurred,
我们就要严肃地谈一谈 没别的意思
we would have a more serious discussion, that's all.
他都被仙人掌扎得遍体鳞伤了 还不够严肃吗
More serious than tearing up his back on a cactus?
古尔科斯是要发动战争
Ghurkos was gonna kill people.
你是不是忘记了
You seem to keep forgetting that--
那我总结一下 你非法闯入博拉维亚
So, in effect, you illegally entered a country,
强行介入有巨大的潜在风险
inserting yourself in the middle
等一下 国际地缘政治冲突
-of an incredibly heated... No, no, no. Hold on.
你选择了支持贾汉普 听我说
-geopolitical situation... Hold on a second.
它和美国关系一向不好
...siding with a nation, Jarhanpur,
现在不一样了
which historically has not been
而你反对的 博拉维亚
-a friend to the US... Jarhanpur has changed.
是我们的正式盟友
...against a nation that's technically our ally,
你还威胁要杀死国家首脑
and then threatened to murder their head of state.
首先 就算贾汉普这个国家有一些问题
First of all, whether or not Jarhanpur is an imperfect country
也不代表别的国家可以侵略它
does not give another nation the right to invade it.
对 但博拉维亚政府的口径
Yes, but the Boravian government maintains
是要把贾汉普人民 从专制政体下解放出来
they're freeing the Jarhanpurians from a tyrannical regime.
可你也知道这都是借口
Yes, but you know that's very silly.
我知道吗
I do?
博拉维亚政府还有脸说别的国家专制
The Boravian government, of all people, is saying this?
别逗了
Come on!
请你记住 这是一次正式采访
This is on the record, Superman.
好了 露易丝
Now-- No. Now, see...
现在是你说话不诚实
Now you're being dishonest, Lois.
我怎么不诚实了
How am I being dishonest?
干什么 怎么关掉 住手
What are you--? Stop. Where's the button?
怎么了 你不诚实 因为我们都清楚
You're being dishonest because you know as well as I do
博拉维亚政府没安好心
that the Boravian government is not well-intentioned.
我认为这种可能性很大 但我能确定吗
I think that's almost certainly the case, but do I know that?
我不能
No, I don't.
可以继续了吗
Can we go on now?
好 可以
Yeah, fine.
你来吧 我
I don't-- You do it. I...
你觉得采访顺利吗
You think this is going well?
该怎么说呢
Do I think this is going well? Um...
至少我这边表现不错
I think I'm doing a good job.
你进入博拉维亚的领空之前 有没有和总统商量过
Superman, did you consult with the President before entering Boravian airspace?
没有 国防部长呢
No. The Secretary of Defense?
没有 那其他的美国高层呢
No. Or any US official
这么说 你完全没问过政府的意见
before you took matters into your own hands
就擅自干涉高度敏感的国际问题
and decided unilaterally how to handle this extremely delicate situation?
古尔科斯和他的帮凶会害死很多人
Ghurkos and his goons were going to kill people.
是的 但你似乎是代表美国在行动
Yes, but the results of you seemingly acting as a representative of the United States will cause...
我不代表任何人 只代表我自己
I wasn't representing anybody...
可能造成更多问题
...more problems around the world.
这是我自己的选择
...except for me, and-and...
我要维护正义 开战最多
More than a war that lasted... ...myself and, and, and...
也就持续12到24小时
...between 12 and 24 hours...
贾汉普本来就是专制政权
...good, I don't know, doing good... and was just replacing
换一个也没区别
one tyrannical regime with another?
你真的这么想吗
Is that really how you feel?
现在接受采访的人不是我 超人 不过
I'm not the one being interviewed, Superman, but...
我会有疑问
I question it.
对 如果我遇到这种情况
Yeah, I would question myself in the same situation
我会停下来问问自己 能不能承担后果
and hold off a beat and consider the consequences.
我不能见死不救
People were going to die!
那我们换个话题吧 你同意吗
Okay, I'd like to change the subject, if I could.
好吧
Okay.
你在社交媒体上的讨论度很高
You've gotten a lot of heat on social media lately.
我都不看那些
I don't read that stuff.
超人可没有时间发自拍
Superman doesn't have time for selfies.
第三人称都用上了
Third person? Hmm?
你还会自己管自己叫超人
You're referring to yourself in the third person now?
没有 我只是突然想到了 下次采访可以用这句
No, it was just a thing I came up with that I thought I'd try to work into the next interview.
你说的每句话都有记录
This is on the record, Superman.
好吧 刚才说的那句不算
Okay, well, not the part where I said that.
刚才那句 也算 不对 那句是题外话
Yes, that part. No, that part was an aside.
是非公开内容
That was off the record.
如果你不想公开 要提前说 不能事后找补
You have to say "off the record" beforehand, not after.
你为什么要对我这样
Why are you being like this?
好 我不会在报道里写 你平时还自己构思互联网金句
Fine, I-I won't write that you spend your spare time trying to think up soundbites.
写出来也太丢人了
Which are terrible, by the way.
说回社交媒体 好
Social media. Yes.
你也许听说了 虽然你宣称从来不看网络评论
As you may know, or maybe you don't, since you claim not to read any of that stuff--
我偶尔看
Very seldomly.
可你就是会偷偷看评论 看了之后还不开心
Maybe sometimes people catch you reading it and looking very upset.
你总不能这样写我吧
Okay, well, you can't use that.
网络上有很多人对你持怀疑态度
People on social media are suspicious because you are...
因为你是外星人 对吗
...an alien, yes?
对 我从没有隐瞒过自己的身份
Yes. I've been very honest about that. From the beginning.
我的故乡叫做氪星
I come from a planet called Krypton.
好的 它现在已经不存在了
Okay. Which is gone now, by the way.
被摧毁了 连同我的过去
Destroyed. Along with all of my history.
我的父母
My parents.
他们为了救我 送我来到这里
They sent me here as a baby to save my life.
这里 是哪儿
Here, where?
我不会说的 你知道我不会说
I'm not gonna say that. You know I'm not gonna say that.
好的
Okay.
你对自己的亲生父母有什么了解吗
What do you know about these biological parents of yours?
我只知道他们送我来 是为了帮助人类
Just that they sent me here to serve humanity
努力让世界变得更好
and to help the world to be a better place.
他们真的说过吗 是的
They said that? They did.
他们留下了一段录像
They sent a message along with me.
那段录像就是我的原动力
That message is why I do what I do.
是我最宝贵的财富
I cherish it more than anything.
你想必也知道
Because you understand now,
现在有很多人认为 你从氪星来到地球
there are an awful lot of people out there maintaining
是出于不可告人的目的
you're here for more nefarious purposes.
网上都叫你超间谍 超烂人
Hashtag Superspy. Hashtag Supershit.
超烂人 拜托
Supershit!? Come on, Lois!
你明明知道我最听不得这个词
You know that one specifically irritates me!
你别忘了 这是正式采访
This is on the record, Clark!
这也不是我编的
I didn't make it up.
网上就是有很多人这么说
It's what people on the Internet are saying.
我要走了
I'm gonna go.
真的吗 对
Really? Yeah.
行了 克拉克 别这样
Come on, Clark. Don't do this.
我并没有怎么样
I'm not doing anything.
没有吗 也不知道是谁采访不顺心 就要撂挑子走人
No? No, that's not you, packing up your shit and walking out of an interview?
我没有撂挑子走人
I'm not walking out of an interview,
只是现在很晚了 每次你遇到冲突 都是这种态度
I'm just-- It's late. No, this is what you do every time you're faced with conflict.
我没什么态度 先是生气
I'm not doing anything. You get mad. You pout.
闹别扭 我没生气
Then you pretend... I'm not mad.
再假装一切正常 就是很正常
...like nothing's wrong. Nothing is wrong.
听着 这次采访够长了
Look, I gave you a nice, long interview.
比我自己的采访还要长得多
Longer than I ever gave myself, by the way.
原来你采访自己还要特意计时呢
Oh, you can time your imaginary interviews with yourself?
教教我怎么做到的
That's a thing you can do?
你拿到了很多素材
You got a lot of good stuff.
有些素材不能用
Some stuff you can't use.
我知道 不用你说
I am well aware.
我就知道我们不可能
I knew this would never work.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
露易丝
Lois?
你想说什么 没什么 就是
What does that mean? Nothing, I just...
我说过 我不擅长谈恋爱
I told you I wasn't good at relationships.
好吧
Okay.
真的是南极耶
The real Antarctica!
太酷了
So cool!
堡垒就在前面
It was right ahead.
可我们怎么进去呢
But how are we going to gain access?
我想进去就能进去
Oh, ye of little faith.
哇
Oh, wow!
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
（氪星语）我们爱你胜过爱天空
超人 我提前就播放录像
Superman, I preemptively put up the soothing--
天啊 真抱歉 这里不对外开放
Oh, my. I do apologize, but this is a restricted area.
等等 我们先谈谈
Wait. Can we talk--
这就是我们要找的
This is what we came for.
希望这里能有些材料 让国防部意识到
Hopefully, there's something on here we can use to convince the general
必须立刻对超人采取措施
Superman requires immediate action.
超人类就够糟了 但都没法和他比
I can't stand the metahumans, but he's so much worse.
超人
Super... man.
他不是人 是异类
He's not a man. He's an it.
他穿着难看的紧身衣
A thing with a cocky grin and a stupid outfit
露出傲慢的笑容 却成了整个世界关注的焦点
that's somehow become the focal point of the entire world's conversation.
自从他出现 一切都不对了
Nothing's felt right since he showed up.
我都明白
I know, Lex.
我舍弃自己的人类身份 就是为了除掉他
I've sacrificed my own humanity to help get rid of it.
能黑进去吗
Can you get in?
需要一些时间
Might take a while.
万一氪星人回来了呢
What if the Kryptonian shows up?
别担心
Don't worry.
我会想办法 拖住他
I'm creating a... distraction.
文森佐维修服务
危险 请勿靠近
怎么了
What?
有一段录像
This message...
是他父母留下的
...from his parents.
（氪星语）那里的人
后半部分损坏了
It's damaged, but there's more.
我可以
It's...
（氪星语）那里的人
我能修复这段录像
I can recover the rest.
（氪星语）那里的人 那里的人
（氪星语）那里的人 那里的人 那里的人
（氪星语）那里的人头脑简单 活得浑浑噩噩
（氪星语）缺乏毅力 身体极为脆弱
成功了
Whoa! Got it!
放它出来
Let it out!
这小东西能管用吗
It's an awfully small distraction.
它会长大的
It'll get bigger.
快走 快点
Get! Go!
快走 快离开这儿
Get! Get outta here!
今天早上人们在咖啡店 第一次见到这只怪兽时
The giant animal was first spotted early this morning
它只有大约两米高
in a Jitters coffee shop about seven feet tall,
突发新闻 攻击大都会的怪兽迅速生长中
随后开始迅速生长
but it has apparently been growing.
你们都没事吧
Everybody okay?
哥们儿 看这里
Hey, buddy. Eyes up here.
女士 慢慢深呼吸 你安全了
Deep, slow breaths, ma'am. You're gonna be fine.
市民朋友们 请迅速撤离
Everybody, clear the area.
他太小气了 说起来就让我生气
He's just so cheap, like, so obnoxious.
星球日报
你能懂吗
You know what I mean?
他能花上千美元 带小女友去音乐会
You can afford $1,000 concert tickets...
在今早的混乱中 终于传来了好消息
Finally a bit of good news amid the chaos here this morning.
突发新闻 超人类团体闪亮登场
正义帮 终于赶到了现场
The Justice Gang has arrived on the scene.
也就是绿灯侠 鹰女还有卓越先生
That's Green Lantern, Hawkgirl and Mr. Terrific.
他们的行动赞助商是劳德科技公司
They're funded by the LordTech corporation.
我们上
Get him!
嘿
Hey!
老实点儿
Heel, boy!
这怪兽什么情况 它的皮很厚 但站不稳
What's the skinny? Its hide is tough, but, uh, it's off balance.
我想尽可能活捉这只怪兽 然后对它进行研究
I've been trying to figure out a way to get it out of here alive.
真是受不了你
Get it someplace where we can study it.
你真是够了 怎么了
Oh, come on, man. What?
攻击它的眼睛
Go for its eyes!
我的膝盖 盖 帮帮我
My knee! Guy, help!
我给它套上了隔热手套
I made giant oven mitts!
你就只顾着自己玩 我都快被它夹死了
Good for you, asshole! I'm getting blinked to death!
拜托 小心一点儿
Come on, be careful!
天哪 一定要这么对它吗
Oh! Good gosh! There's gotta be a better way to do this.
太凶残了
Come on.
突发新闻 怪兽已被超人类击杀
相关部门表示 多亏了超人的鼎力相助
Authorities are saying there haven't been any signs yet of loss of life,
本次事件并未造成人员伤亡
thanks to Metropolis hometown hero, Superman,
但财产损失高达上百万元
but the damage to property could be in the millions.
市政府发言人
City spokespeople...
你约的那个男的怎么样了
How's it going with that guy you were seeing?
之前你说你还没想好
You were saying you weren't sure about it?
是啊 因为他
Yeah. He's...
有点怪怪的
a little strange.
不知道它的肉 味道怎么样
Ooh! Kaiju steaks all around, huh?
我本来想活捉这个怪兽 送去星际动物园
I was hoping we could capture it and take it to an intergalactic zoo or...
至少不该让它死得这么痛苦
...at least euthanize it less painfully.
得了吧 别这么软蛋
Come on, bro. Don't be such a wuss.
我们正义帮就是喜欢行侠仗义 大家别误会
'Ey! Just another day in the life of the Justice Gang!
这不是正式队名
Not our name.
那只是暂时的称号
It's just a working name.
和正式队名也没区别
Could very well prove to be permanent though.
区别大了 反正最后肯定选这个名字
Probably not! Good chance though, I'm saying.
小朋友们 没受伤吧
You okay? Everybody okay?
我只想代表劳德科技公司 感谢大家能给予我们
Just like to say thank you on behalf of LordTech Industries for the opportunity--
怎么没人鼓掌
Why is nobody clapping?
超人来地球是为了毁灭人类
快点过来
Come here.
这事儿也太扯了吧
This has to be BS.
确定没搞错吗
Well, they couldn't be mistaken?
没有
Oh, no.
如果是真的 那就太可怕了
Well, that sounds very disturbing, Lex.
根据28名顶尖语言学家的说法
Twenty-eight of the world's top linguists
星球新闻
这个翻译很准确
have confirmed the translation
30名计算机取证专家也证实
and 30 of the top forensic computer techs
这段录像不是伪造的
have confirmed the validity of the footage itself.
有没有可能是搞错了
Any chance they're mistaken?
很遗憾的是 没有
Unfortunately, no.
能放录像吗 可以
You have the footage? Yes.
一起看一下
Let's take a look.
（氪星语）我们爱你胜过爱天空
超人来地球是为了毁灭人类
我们爱你胜过爱天空
We love you more than heaven, our son.
爱你胜过爱大地
We love you more than land.
不久后 我们深爱的家园 将要永远消失
Our beloved home is soon to be gone forever.
马里炸豆丸子
超人来地球是为了毁灭人类
但希望点亮了我们的心
But hope vitalizes our hearts,
希望就是你 卡-艾尔
and that hope is you, Kal-El.
我们选了一颗星球做你的家 你要多做好事
We have searched the universe for a home where you can do the most good.
不要忘记氪星的真理
And live out Krypton's truth.
那颗星球就是地球
That place is Earth.
这些话有哪里不好吗
I don't get it. What's bad about that?
（氪星语）那里的人 那里的人
那里的人头脑简单 活得浑浑噩噩
The people there are simple and profoundly confused.
缺乏毅力 身体极为脆弱
Weak of mind and spirit and body.
你是氪星唯一的后代 你要成为他们的主人
Lord over the planet as the last son of Krypton.
凡是不愿意服从你的人 全部杀无赦
Dispatch of anyone unable or unwilling to serve you, Kal-EI.
尽量多娶一些妻子
Take as many wives as you can,
让氪星人的基因遍布各地 续写我们的传奇
so your genes and Krypton's might and legacy
去统治地球吧
will live on in this new frontier.
亲爱的儿子 不用手下留情
Do us proud, our beloved son. Rule without mercy.
可是这些年来 超人做了很多好事
But what about all the kind acts Superman has performed over the years,
他救了太多人了
saving countless lives?
不 他在对我们洗脑
No. He's grooming us.
他假装友善 让我们放松警惕
Lulling us into complacency,
不费吹灰之力就能制服我们
so he can dominate without resistance,
等时机到了之后 他的子孙后代就可以统治地球
forging a path for his super-powered descendants to rule the Earth.
我绝对不会让他的阴谋得逞 你呢
I will not accept that. Will you?
你怎么了 说实话
You seem upset. I'm...
我很害怕
I'm scared.
我的心里充满了恐惧
I will admit that, I am scared.
谁知道超人的秘密后宫 到底有多少人了
Because who knows how large his secret harem is already?
史塔格工业
别挡着我 让我进去 我没开玩笑
Oh, hell no! Let me in! I'm serious!
哥们儿 你真的有后宫吗
Dude, you got a secret harem?
我怎么可能有那种东西
No, Guy, of course I don't have a harem.
如果刚才那段录像说的是真的
If any of that message is even remotely true,
那你就是我的敌人
then you are exactly the kind of alien threat
正因为存在你这种外星威胁 绿灯军团才派我来守护地球
I was commandeered by the Green Lantern Corps to protect this planet against.
别惹我 盖
Back off, Guy! Oh.
有种就打我啊
Make a move, Big Blue.
盖 冷静点儿
Guy, relax.
那段录像是真的吗
Was the message real or not?
前半段确实是 真的
The first half. The first half is... is real.
我不确定 后半段之前文件损坏了
The second half was damaged in the t-trip from Krypton to Earth.
肯定是伪造的 不可能 克拉克
So it's-it's gotta be doctored. No way, Clark.
我了解计算机取证专家
I know these computer forensics guys.
如果没有十足的把握 他们不会说是真的
They're not gonna say it's legit unless they are sure.
我很遗憾 兄弟
I'm so sorry, man,
那段录像不是伪造的
but there's no way that message is fake.
他们从哪儿拿到的录像
Where'd they get the footage though?
您打算逮捕超人进行审问吗
Are you considering bringing Superman in for questioning?
这要和总统商量
We're talking with the President,
这件事需要谨慎考虑
and we are reviewing our options now.
很抱歉 我必须要挂电话了 莱恩小姐
I'm sorry, but I have to go, Miss Lane.
如果你要审问 什么时候
And if you did, when would that--
你相信吗
You buying this?
瑞克 我从不相信卢瑟
I don't put anything past Luthor, Rick.
但那段录像确实是真的
But the message is authentic.
如果氪星人真是威胁 我们得采取行动
If the Kryptonian is a danger, we have to act.
我本来是超人的粉丝
I was a big Superman fan.
超人露出了真面目
我以前很支持他 但现在
I supported him all the time online and stuff, but now?
我希望他下地狱
I mean, I hope he rots in hell.
我不管 赶紧去那儿
I don't care. You're supposed to get out!
快去拍照片
Get me some pictures.
就快要截稿了
We have a deadline!
他在哪儿 快过去
Where is he? Get there now!
不要叫我老大
Don't call me Chief.
行吧 我去干活儿
Okay. I'm gonna do my job.
我现在终于明白 氪星人
It's no wonder the Kryptonian
为什么要干预博拉维亚的计划了
interfered with Boravia's interests.
我们之所以向贾汉普派兵 是想拯救那里的人民
Boravia wants to save the people of Jarhanpur.
但超人却想要让他们继续当奴隶
And Superman wants to keep them enslaved!
博拉维亚领导人谴责超人
不过 我还听说一件事儿
Also, from what I hear,
他觉得 博拉维亚的女性是全世界最美最迷人的
he finds Boravian women the most physically attractive
想要将她们也加入那个秘密后宫
and wants to add them to his secret harem.
我有个问题 古尔科斯总统
I have a question, President Ghurkos.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
您讲得太好了 总统先生
[in Boravian] That couldn't have gone better, Mr. President!
您真是英俊无比 活力四射
You were so handsome and dynamic!
太棒了
Wonderful!
太帅了 帅死了
Very handsome! Very handsome!
行了 不要跟进来
Go! Leave me be!
成功了 莱克斯
We did it, Lex!
等真的干掉超人之后再庆祝吧
I wouldn't celebrate until the alien is off the board.
对了 我带了甜甜圈 这家店很好吃
Oh, here. I brought you a donut. From Dough's Holes.
在帕克里奇新开的
New shop in Park Ridge, of all places.
伪造录像 真是个天才的想法
The fake message, a stroke of genius.
那不是伪造的
It's not fake.
超人想杀掉我们 我早就知道
He is here to kill us. I knew it!
我去超人的堡垒
At Superman's fortress,
想找到他的弱点干掉他
I hoped to get the knowledge to help destroy him.
没想到最后是他父母帮了我这一把
Little did I know, his own parents would be providing it.
真好吃
Oh.
对吧 对
Right? Yeah.
我想我那半贾汉普上也该开一家
Been thinking of opening one in my half of Jarhanpur.
四号 四号 怎么回事
Four. Four. What happened?
我想要保护超人
I tried to protect Superman.
没有我的基因 卢瑟应该进不来啊
How did Luthor get in here? It's keyed into my DNA.
必须保护超人
Must protect Superman.
四号
Four.
我很抱歉 我的朋友
I'm sorry, friend.
小氪
Krypto?
Krypto!
卢瑟集团
对 那是必须的
Well, yeah, that's gonna become--
我努力阻止过他了 没关系 希瑟
Lex, I tried to stop him. It's fine, Heather.
超人 真是幸会
Superman, we finally meet.
你要咖啡还是茶 我的狗呢
Would you like a coffee or tea? Where's the dog?
狗
Dog?
别装傻了 把狗还给我
The dog, Luthor! You took the dog!
干得好 伊芙 全都录下来
That's right, Eve, get all of this.
把狗还给我
Where's the dog?
抱歉 我根本不清楚 你到底在说什么
I have no clue what you're talking about.
它只是条狗
He's just a dog.
我不知道你说的是哪条狗
I don't know what dog you're talking about.
系着披风那个吗
Ugly dog in a cape?
你刚说什么
What did you say? Hmm?
我什么都没说
I didn't say anything.
你们都听到了
You heard what he said!
外星人威胁莱克斯·卢瑟总裁
我的狗 被他偷了
You heard him! He took him!
不好意思 在我看来
I mean, it seems to me,
超人此时此刻的表现 就像是一只疯狗
that the only rabid animal around here is Superman.
自从氪星人统治地球的计划曝光后
Ever since the discovery of the Kryptonian's master plan,
你超人也不装了 你说呢 克里斯
he's gone off the deep end. Thoughts, Chris?
我其实一点也不吃惊
Can't say I'm surprised, Cleavis.
像他这样的人 背后总有一些 黑暗丑陋的秘密
It's guys like this, they always got a whole bunch of dark, ugly secrets.
像他这样的人 是指什么
What do you mean, "guys like this?"
以为自己比别人高一等
Thinks he's better than everybody else.
他还公开发言 说如果理由不充分 绝不能剥夺他人性命
Makes this declaration he's against killing people unless it's absolutely necessary.
装什么
Really, dude?
老爸老妈 22个未接来电
自己站在道德高地上
It kinda sounds like you're trying to make the guys
天天指责别人 这样没意思
who are a little more edgier than you look like jerks.
明白吗
Know what I mean? Mm-hmm.
他们很多人 就是 那些超级英雄
A lot of these guys, these... heroes from the magazines,
都迷恋我
they're obsessed with me.
我比他们帅多了
'Cause I'm more jacked than they are.
他们也知道
They know they don't have--
你还养狗
You have a dog?
不是我养的 我只是暂时 照顾它一段时间
No, not really. It's more of a... foster situation.
喝吧
Cocoa.
你刚才在帮他们吗
You were out there helping them?
没有 那个
Oh, no, that's just, uh--
就是个五维生物
That's just some dimensional imp.
他们能搞定 我刚才在找狗
They've got that handled. I was looking for the dog.
你还好吗
You okay?
那段录像不是你想的那样
The footage is not what it looks like, Lois.
好的
Okay.
我父母留下的录像在飞行途中损坏了
The ship my parents sent me in was damaged in transit,
所以我只看过前半部分
so I only ever heard the first part of the message.
我没有想到后半部分是这样
And I believed I knew how it ended.
我以为我到这里来是为了帮助地球人
That my parents had sent me here to serve the people of Earth
做一个好人
and to be a good man.
我来这里不是为了统治任何人
I'm not here to rule over anybody, Lois.
我也从没这么想过 一次也没有 克拉克
I never thought you were, even for a moment, Clark.
真好喝
Oh, that's really good.
咱俩没吵架就好了
I'm sorry we fought.
是啊
Me too.
不过吵架也很正常
But we're bound to, though.
我们太不一样了
We're so different.
我是贝克林区的朋克摇滚少年 而你
I was just some punk rock kid from Bakerline, and you're...
你是超人
Superman.
我也喜欢朋克摇滚 你才不喜欢朋克摇滚呢
I'm punk rock. You are not punk rock.
我喜欢窒息乐队 波兹乐队 还有无敌蟹棒
I like the Strangle-Fellows, and the P.O.D.s and the Mighty Crabjoys.
那些都是流行乐队 不是玩朋克摇滚的
Those are pop radio bands. They're not punk rock.
你还听无敌蟹棒 难听死了
The Mighty Crabjoys suck.
喜欢他们的人也挺多的
Okay, well, a lot of people love 'em.
我习惯了质疑每一件事 每一个人
My point is, I question everything and everyone.
而你 信任每一个人 你还觉得遇到的每一个人都很
You trust everyone and think everyone you've ever met is, like...
很美好
beautiful.
也许这才是朋克摇滚精神
Maybe that's the real punk rock.
你那天说 我们不可能 你真的这么想吗
Lois, what did you mean when you said that you knew this would never work?
我不知道
I don't know.
我得走了
I'm gonna go.
司法部发布了我的通缉令
The DOJ has a warrant out for my arrest,
我准备去自首
so I'm gonna turn myself in.
等等 什么 为什么
Wait, what? Why?
他们也许会带我去狗那里
Maybe they'll take me wherever they took the dog.
我没有别的办法了
I don't know how else to find him.
就为了只狗
It's a dog.
虽然它平常很调皮 但是
Yeah, and he's not even a very good one, but...
我不能丢下它
he's out there alone.
它肯定吓坏了
And he's probably scared.
我爱你 露易丝
I love you, Lois.
抱歉 拖到现在才告诉你
I probably should have told you that a long time ago.
有必要这样吗
Is that necessary?
我都过来自首了
I'm coming in on my own accord.
不用读米兰达权利吗
No one read me my rights.
美国法律规定 那些权利不适用于外星生物
Courts decided those rights don't apply to extraterrestrial organisms.
所以现阶段来说 你没有任何权利
Therefore, at this point, Superman, you don't have any rights to read.
考虑到你的能力
The government is very well aware
政府已经下令将关押审问你的事宜
of the potential limitations detaining you, so we've outsourced your confinement
全权交给星球守卫者
and your interrogation to PlanetWatch.
星球守卫者
PlanetWatch?
对不住了
I'm sorry about this.
（歌词大意）让你的怀抱 就像太阳一样温暖
给我快乐
给我阳光 给我爱
♪ Bring me sunshine Bring me love ♪
用你的微笑 带给我阳光
♪ Bring me sunshine In your eyes ♪
从天空上 带给我彩虹
♪ Bring me a rainbow From the sky ♪
人生苦短 不如尽情享受快乐
♪ Life's too short to be spent Having anything but fun ♪
只要有一缕阳光 我们就会满足
♪ We can be so content If we gather little sunbeams ♪
不要烦恼
♪ Be light-hearted ♪
放松心情
♪ All day long ♪
嘿
Hey!
放声唱出 快乐之歌
♪ Keep me singing Happy songs ♪
我们又见面了 真是荣幸
Twice in two days. What a pleasure.
卢瑟
Luthor.
你怎么像变态一样总缠着我
Your obsession with me is getting a little creepy.
别担心 我对火星帅哥没兴趣
Don't worry. Tall, dark, and Martian isn't my type.
是氪星 都一样
Kryptonian. Eh, same diff.
这是哪儿
Where are we?
口袋宇宙
A pocket universe.
我用卢瑟集团的巨型对撞机 重现了宇宙大爆炸
I replicated the Big Bang with a LuthorCorp mega-collider,
在两个宇宙间撕开一个小洞 也就是这里
tearing a tiny hole between the two universal fabrics.
全球各地都设有维度传送门
I'm able to access it from multiple dimensional portals
方便我随时来口袋宇宙
I've set up around the globe.
这是雷克斯 他也是超人类 被称为元素人
Rex, the metahuman known as the Element Man,
我特意请他过来帮我一个小忙
has been called into service for a specific purpose.
他能变形成任何已知的物质
He can metamorphose into any known substance.
甚至可以变成 外太空的物质 比如说
Even substances foreign to this planet, like...
氪石
...Kryptonite.
瓦西尔·古尔科斯再次派兵 前往贾汉普边境
Once again, Vasil Ghurkos is sending troops to the Jarhanpurian border.
突发新闻 博拉维亚军队向贾汉普边境前进
超人刚被抓没多久
Superman's been out of commission
博拉维亚就想要搞事了
less than a day, and already Boravia's pulling this crap?
国际版
你说呢 什么
Right? What?
抱歉 我刚在研究莱克斯·卢瑟和这件事有什么联系
Sorry, I'm trying to figure out how Lex Luthor's connected to all this.
更好的世界
那还用说吗
How's that a mystery?
卢瑟卖武器给博拉维亚 让两国开战
LuthorCorp sells arms to Boravia, Boravia goes to war,
他就能狂卖军火赚更多钱
Luthor sells more arms and gets richer than ever.
不对 不对吗
Nope. No?
不对
Uh-uh.
我在博达银行有线人
I have a connection at BodaBank.
他调查过卢瑟集团和博拉维亚之间的交易
Boda handles the transactions between LuthorCorp and Boravia.
卢瑟集团确实出售了 将近800亿美元的军火
Yes, LuthorCorp sold them approximately 80 billion dollars' worth of arms,
但你猜怎么着
but for those arms,
博拉维亚只支付了16.25亿美元
Boravia paid only 1.625 billion dollars.
卢瑟白送他们武器 为什么
So Luthor gave them arms for free? For what?
肯定有什么理由 让他愿意亏损783.75亿美元
That's the 78 billion, 375-million-dollar question.
你知道超人被关在哪里吗
Have you found out where they're holding Superman?
政府的人都不肯说
No one in the government'll say.
这样看来 卢瑟设法囚禁超人
Luthor seems to be working to disable Superman
是为了让他无法阻止对贾汉普的侵略
just so he can't stop the invasion of Jarhanpur.
为什么
Why?
露易丝 你糖放太多了
That's way too much sugar, Lois.
我们摇滚青年就要放致死量
I party like a rock star, choir boy.
这咖啡还是苦得要命
Still can't hide the taste of petroleum.
天啊
God!
变异脚趾
别这么渣 吉米 做个人行不行
超人被卢瑟关进了口袋宇宙
Lex is holding Superman in a pocket universe.
什么东西
A what?
不知道 我的线人也不知道那是什么
I don't know what a pocket universe is. Neither does my source.
那家伙基本上什么也不懂
They don't know anything about anything, really.
不过 超人肯定在口袋宇宙
But for sure he's in a pocket universe.
是哪个线人
Who's your source?
我不能说 不过 你欠我人情
I can't say, but you owe me.
大人情
Big time.
说真的
Like...
为这件事我牺牲了太多
I can't even tell you how big.
吉米·奥尔森 爱你哦 你太棒了 我也爱你
I love you, Jimmy Olsen. I love you. Love you.
嗨 想不想见面
这些猴子机器人是我的网络水军
Just my Monkey-Bots here, farming outrage 24/7.
负责没日没夜地抹黑你
Trashing you online.
原来超烂人是它们写的
Hashtag Supershit.
只有脑残才会继续粉超人
那个超烂人想杀光地球人
秘密后宫
小氪
Krypto.
怎么才能困住超级小狗
How do you contain a super dog?
让它去追超级松鼠就好了
You beam super squirrels into its brain.
我们正在研究它
We'll learn what we can.
等研究完 就该跟它拜拜了
Then we'll put the varmint down.
它会死得很痛苦
It will undoubtedly be painful.
卢瑟先生 求你了 我保证
Mr. Luthor, please! I swear...
你现在看到的 是我的私人监狱
This is our private correctional institution.
大部分牢房都租借给了政府
Yeah, most cells are rented out to governments
专门用来关押
who want to keep their incarcerations
那些喜欢批评抹黑政府的暴民
of political agitators private.
其他牢房关的是我的仇人
Others are for more personal transgressions.
比如弗勒莱特 写了关于我的小作文
Fleurette wrote a blog about me.
我最讨厌分手了还放不下的前女友
There are few things I hate more than petty ex-girlfriends.
你说这些是因为
You wouldn't be telling me any of this if you--
因为我不打算放你出去 没错
If we ever planned on letting you out? No.
要我说 应该直接干掉你
You'd be terminated already if it was up to me.
但政府那边有些问题想问你
First, the government has some questions they want answered.
雷克斯 看看这是谁
Rex. Look who it is.
你最好别让超人跑了
You be sure to keep our guest in check.
不然小约瑟夫也会不开心哦
Little Joseph certainly wouldn't want it any other way.
明天我再过来审问超人
I'll be back tomorrow to get the answers we need.
小帅哥
Hey, handsome.
来认识一下
Come on over.
嗨 嗨 伊芙
Hi! Hey, Eve.
抱歉叫你来这里
Oh, sorry we had to meet here,
但莱克斯总喜欢用交通摄像头监视我
but Lex is always accessing traffic cameras, so he knows where I am.
这种烂人 你怎么还不跟他分手
I really don't understand why you stay in that relationship.
因为他警告过我 他把所有前女友都关进了口袋宇宙
'Cause he made a point to tell me about all his ex-girlfriends he had imprisoned in his pocket universe.
什么 很吓人吧
What? Right?
你妈妈好吗 我妈妈
How's your mom? My mom?
我超级爱她
Oh, I love her so much.
她就像我的亲妈一样 甚至还要亲
I think of her as my mom, even more than my own mother.
我妈妈也这么想
Oh, she feels the same way,
虽然 你们就见过一次面
from the-the one time that you guys met.
真的吗 我们说正事吧 好啊
Yeah? So, hey. Okay.
伊芙 什么
Yes. Yes. Eve?
你男朋友和博拉维亚似乎有一些关系
There seems to be some sort of connection between Boravia and your boyfriend.
我不清楚
I'm not clear on what-- Oh.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你不高兴吗
What's "oh"?
我还以为你约我出来 是想见我呢 吉米
I thought you wanted to see me, Jimmy.
我是很想你
I do but, Eve,
但莱克斯是你男朋友 肯定要提到他的
how could I even really see you with Lex still in the picture?
你约我出来就是想套我的话
You're just trying to get information out of me.
你误会我了
I swear to God, that's not it.
我只是觉得如果能挖到他的黑料
I-I just know that if I could get some real dirt on him,
也许我们两个
then maybe the two of us could--
就能重新在一起
Could be together again?
是啊
Yeah.
可你之前说 我的脚趾长得像深海大虾
But you said my toes look like someone spilled shrimp cocktail on the floor.
你的脚趾有点特别 那不重要
You have unconventional toes. Who cares?
你其他部分都很漂亮 能迷死一堆人
There's other parts of you that people would find very attractive.
莱克斯那天还欺负小狗
Lex tortured a dog the other day.
天啊 这什么烂人 可不是吗
Jesus Christ! I know.
我得走了 伊芙
I have to go. Eve.
求你帮我找找线索
Please see what you can find out.
好吧 太好了 谢谢
Okay. Yes! Yes!
拜拜
Okay.
飞吻收到 放心吧
I'm-I'm putting 'em in my pocket.
拜拜
Okay.
约瑟夫是你儿子
Joseph. He's your son?
不要跟我说话
Don't talk to me.
求你了
Please.
我可以飞出去接他过来
I could fly over and get him if you just--
只要没有氪石
if you'd stop with the Kryptonite.
没办法离开这儿的 所以
There's no way out of here, okay? So, just...
总会有办法 我说了 别说话
There's always a way. I said don't talk to me!
你自找的
I told you.
不要 跟我说话
Don't talk to me!
正义大厅
你想让我干什么
Yeah, so what do you want me to do?
《星球日报》美国违反日内瓦公约
将超人囚禁在口袋宇宙 作者 露易丝·莱恩
奶精在哪儿
Where's the creamer?
和平常一样 在桌子上
On the counter, where it always is.
他是你们的队友 对吧
He's in your group, right? The, um, uh--
你们叫什么来着 正义帮
What's it called, again? The Justice Gang.
不是 我们不叫那个
No. We're not called that.
得了 你叫卓越先生
Yeah, your name is Mr. Terrific.
你哪知道什么叫好名字
You don't get a vote with a name like that.
别忘了我也投反对票
I also voted against it.
我知道 但我是队长 能投决定票
Yes. And as leader, I get tiebreaker.
超人不是我们的正式队员
No, Superman is not officially a member.
因为你知道他也会反对这个名字
Because you don't want him to vote. You know which way that would go.
住嘴 他开玩笑的
Shut up. He's kidding.
不过 能问一下你怎么认识超人的吗
So, how do you even know Superman anyway?
我就是认识
I... just... do.
你也知道催眠眼镜的事情吗
So you know about the hypno-glasses?
现在她知道了
Now she does.
我又没说超人是谁 只说他戴催眠眼镜
I'm not saying who he is, just that he wears hypno-glasses.
那个眼镜
They make his face...
能让他怎样来着
Terrific, how do they work?
他戴上眼镜 你们就会被催眠 意识不到他其实就是超人
They make his face look different in your brain when he wears them.
没错 我知道这件事
So that you don't know who he is.
但你真的不该告诉我
Yes, I know this, first of all.
万一我还不知道你说的是谁呢
But, second of all, you really shouldn't be telling me this in case I don't know who he is.
你知道他是克拉克·肯特
So, you know he's Clark Kent?
天啊 他怎么谁都相信
Oh, my God. Why does he trust everyone?
他只告诉了我们 因为我们穿衣品味很像
He doesn't. Just us because we are also of the cloth.
哪里像了
"Of the cloth?"
接下来我们该怎么办 什么怎么办
What are we gonna do? About what?
去救超人啊 他不是你们的朋友吗
Superman! He's your friend!
什么朋友 他想统治我们呢
Some friend. Came here to rule over me?
很难找到他
It would be difficult to find him.
我之前把纳米追踪器 植入了超人的血液里
I put nanobot GPS trackers into Superman's bloodstream.
他的踪迹在克莱默堡这里突然消失了
You can see where his trail ends abruptly right here at Fort Kramer,
搜寻基因中
那儿是个军事哨所 在河对面16公里处
a dormant military post across the river about ten miles down.
哪怕他已经死了 那里也该有信号
Even if he was dead, those trackers would still be there.
所以 我赞同你在报纸上做出的推测
So, all this leads me to believe, as your article surmised,
他被关进了口袋宇宙
he really is in a pocket universe.
你往超人的血液里植入了纳米追踪器
You put nanobot GPS trackers in your friend's bloodstream?
其他人身上也有
Oh, I do that to everybody.
好吧 那赶紧去克莱默堡
So, okay. Come on. Let's go to Fort Kramer then.
我们四个一起去找出真相
The four of us, and find out what's going on.
找到以后要做什么
And then do what?
把超人救出来
Save him.
你想擅自把 联邦政府关押的犯人放出来吗
You wanna break a federally incarcerated prisoner out of jail?
听好 他们囚禁超人是因为 他想阻止博拉维亚发动侵略
Look, I think this is being done to keep him from interfering with the Boravian invasion.
你才该听好 我是绿灯侠 知道吗
No, you look. I'm a Green Lantern, lady.
我当初发过誓 绝不掺和政治上的事
That means I took a vow not to get involved in politics.
你发誓还说了这句吗
Oh, that's part of the vows?
差不多吧 怎么了
It's implied. Yeah.
发誓还能差不多
An implied vow?
他每次不想干什么 就说自己发过誓
Every time there's something he doesn't want to do, he says it's part of some vow.
你们两个别太过分
Oh, I swear to God.
小心我创造出一把巨锤 把你们砸死
I am two seconds away from forming a giant hammer, and beating you both to death.
超人真想统治世界吗
Is Supes here to take over the world?
我觉得应该不是真的
I don't know. Probably not.
但救他风险太大了 正义帮可不想和美国政府结仇
But the risk is just not worth the beef between the US government and the Justice Gang.
我们才不叫这么土的名字
Not our name. Makes us sound like cowboys.
不过其他的我都同意
But I agree with the rest.
你们就这样对朋友见死不救吗
So you're just gonna let your friend rot in a pocket universe?
你不如发誓 再也别留那个发型
That haircut should be against your vows.
什么
That what?
你刚才说什么
That what should be what?
你给我听好了 有348个妹子夸过我的发型
I'll have you know 348 chicks say otherwise.
嘿
Hey!
干什么
What?
我没打算要救他 不过 公平竞争
I'm not saying we're gonna save him, but...
我可以去克莱默堡 看看你男朋友到底怎么了
...I think we can at least check out what's going on with your boyfriend at this Fort Kramer.
他还
He's not--
不算我男朋友
We're just seeing each other.
谢谢
But thanks.
我来开车吗
You want me to drive?
还是坐我的车吧
We'll take my ride.
卓越
你都有飞行器了 就不能让车库门开快点儿吗
You have a flying saucer, but you couldn't get a faster garage door?
我最近没有空
I haven't worked on that yet.
我不知道该怎么想 真的
I'm not even sure how I feel. Honestly.
什么 我是说克拉克
What? About Clark.
他不是我的男朋友
He's not my boyfriend.
我们才刚约会了几个月而已
We've actually just been seeing each other...
不好意思 我得说清楚
Yeah, lady, just to be clear, ...for a couple of months--
我不想听你的感情问题
I'm not into people's emotions.
好 没问题
Yeah, no, totally.
你就当我是自言自语
I'm just thinking out loud.
我本来想跟他分手
I was gonna break up with him, actually.
那天 我们两个大吵了一架
I mean, we had this huge fight,
他说他爱我 但是 我感觉
and he told me he loved me, and it just didn't...
外星人 该回答问题了
Q and A time, alien.
今天来了一位贵客
Today we have a special guest.
我记得他
I'm familiar with him.
我带他飞过沙漠时 他尿裤子了
And the smell of his piss as we flew across the desert.
他在胡说八道
That is a lie!
贵客不是瓦西尔 他只是来参观
No, not Vasil. He's just here as an observer.
马里
Mali.
听着 美国政府有几个问题要问你
Now, the US government has a few questions for you.
卢瑟 我跟他不熟 他只是请我吃过东西
Luthor, I barely know him. He gave me food one time.
你在地球上的同伙是谁
Who are you working with here on Earth?
我根本没有同伙 卢瑟
I'm not working with anyone, Luthor.
超人 什么都不要说
Don't tell him nothing, Superman.
反正我没有家人
I have no family or nothing.
卢瑟 放过他吧
Luthor, don't do this.
能请你吃东西是我的荣幸
You eating my food was a great honor, Superman.
不 放过他吧 刚才算他走运
Ooh. No. Got lucky on that one. No, please.
不 卢瑟 别这样 求你了
No, Luthor, don't do this. Please.
这样吧 我换一个问题好了
Let's try another question, shall we, Superman?
卢瑟 放了他 你小时候 谁收养了你
Luthor, don't do this. Who raised you as a child?
我不能说 我相信你 超人
I can't. I believe in you, Superman!
不 不要告诉他
No! Don't tell him--
没想到这么快就中奖了
I didn't imagine that would go so quickly.
抱歉 实在是
I'm sorry, it's...
英俊先生
Mr. Handsome.
凡是和你交谈过的人 我都会一个个带过来杀掉
I'll be back later with someone else you've chatted with, and I'll kill them too.
我记得有个记者总是喜欢采访你
Maybe that reporter you always do interviews with.
下一个就杀克拉克·肯特好了
Maybe I'll kill Clark Kent next.
不 怎么会这样
No, no, no, no.
（歌词大意）用不了五年 我们会去动物园
卢瑟集团
温暖的阳光照着我和你
♪ ...over me and you ♪
大象的身体里
♪ And there'll be love In the bodies ♪
也充满了爱
♪ Of the elephants too ♪
我遮住你的眼睛
♪ And I'll put my hands Over your eyes ♪
但你还在偷看
♪ But you'll peep through ♪
温暖的阳光 洒满我们全身
温暖的阳光 抚摸我们的脖子
温暖的阳光 照耀我们的脸庞
♪ And there'll be sun, sun, sun All over our faces ♪
这里是禁区
Restricted area, pal!
请你们马上离开这里
Get back to your vehicle and get out of here!
胆子不小嘛
Whoa! What do we got here?
他在干什么
Hey! You see this guy?
是疯了吧
Unbelievable.
嘿
Hey! Um...
哥们儿 你来错地方了
You at the wrong address, bro.
他的移动路径
That's his path.
一直通向那个帐篷
DNA trail leads to that tent.
快点儿离开
Keep moving, clown.
那小子不是正义帮的吗
Isn't that one of those Justice guys?
他是那个出主意的
It's just the smart one.
你听不见吗
Hey! You heard the man.
我现在最后一次警告你 马上停下
I am giving you one last chance to stop!
我也正要警告你呢
I was just about to say the same to you.
开火
Fire!
干掉他
（歌词大意）那时多么快乐 忘记时间
♪ It was fun, fun, fun Oh, it was fun ♪
撤退 先撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
都让开
Get out of the way!
掩护我
Cover me!
我看着你 说我真是无比幸福
侧面包抄
Flank right!
我会说
♪ And she'll say ♪
我不再需要装酷
♪ "Yeah, well, I feel All pretty happy too ♪
她会说 我也很开心
♪ And I'm always pretty happy ♪
我和你在一起时
♪ When I'm just Kicking back with you" ♪
总是很幸福 爱意充满我们的身体
♪ And it'll be love, love, love All through our bodies ♪
爱意
♪ And love, love, love ♪
当心 充满我们的心
Look out! ♪ All through our minds ♪
爱意洋溢在她的脸庞
♪ Love, love, love All over her face ♪
也洋溢在
♪ Love, love, love ♪
我的脸上
♪ All over mine ♪
虽然这些场面
♪ Although admittedly All these moments ♪
只是我的想象
♪ Are just in my head ♪
我躺在床上 不断畅想
♪ I'll be thinking about them As I'm lying in bed ♪
我知道所有这些 也许不会成真
♪ And I know that admittedly It might not even come true ♪
但在脑海中 我们多么幸福
♪ But in my mind I'm havin' A pretty good time with you ♪
五年后 也许我不认识你
五年后 也许我们不说话
我真是服了
Holy shit.
五年后 也许我们关系很差
五年后 也许你会证明我错了
难以置信
Unbelievable.
那混蛋还真的造了一个口袋宇宙
That jackass did create a pocket universe.
情况不妙 是吗
And that's... bad?
创造口袋宇宙的时候
When creating a pocket universe,
只要发生一丁点儿偏差
if you are just one picometer off,
地球就会原地消失 变成一个黑洞
you will have a black hole where Earth used to be.
每一次有人进出口袋宇宙
And every time you enter or exit,
都有可能把现实撕开一道口子
you risk tearing a hole in the fabric of reality.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
莱克斯·卢瑟一直在做危险的研究
It's the type of reckless science Lex Luthor specializes in.
那玩意儿在干什么
What are they doing?
想办法黑进去
They're trying to hack it.
这么说你愿意帮他了
So, I guess you decided to help.
我只是想跟绿灯侠对着干
Only because it'll piss off Green Lantern.
谢谢
Thanks.
那个人就这么被他杀了
He just killed that poor guy.
马里 他的名字叫马里
Mali. His name was Mali.
可是我 就这么看着
And I didn't... I-- I didn't...
我什么都没有做
I didn't do anything.
你真的能救出我儿子吗
You said you can get to my son, right?
噢
Ooh.
你的脸怎么还这么难看
Why are you still gross-looking?
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得
I thought that...
我需要晒太阳
It must be the sun.
你说什么 什么太阳 这里没有太阳
What are you-- What sun? There's no sun here.
那就麻烦了 我需要恢复
That's the problem. I need to heal.
我的力量来自黄太阳
I get my powers from the yellow sun.
别急 等我一下
Just... give me a second.
振作点儿
Come on!
真不错 能进了
Hell, yeah. We're in.
反质子都流成河了
Whoa! An antiproton river.
要吊根绳下去吗 吊根绳
Do we rappel? Rappel?
我上哪儿找能吊在口袋宇宙里的绳子
Where am I gonna get the gear to rappel into a pocket universe?
你不是有很多装备 就是那些圆圈什么的
I don't know. Maybe it comes out of your... circles or something.
圆圈 怎么了
Circles? What?
是卓越球 好
T-spheres. Okay.
球是立体的 圆圈是平的
They're three-dimensional. Circles are flat.
对不起
Sorry.
真没常识
Unbelievable.
这里到处是黑洞旋涡
This place is filthy with black hole vortexes,
要是掉进反质子河 我们会瞬间被分解成粒子
and that antiproton river will tear us apart in seconds.
没有必要进去送死
We cannot go in ourselves.
明白
Copy.
我变不成太阳
I can't make a sun.
我知道
I know.
我只能变成和太阳很像的东西
I can only make something kind of like a sun.
什么 我试试
What? All right.
好的
Okay.
我有 氢元素 还有氘元素
Okay, we got hydrogen, and deuterium.
还有氦元素
And we got helium.
把它们压缩到一起 你在做什么
And compression, obviously. What are you doing?
不 住手 快停下
Hey! Hey, no, no. Stop!
你这样会连累到我们的
Enough! You're, you're gonna get all of us in trouble!
你干什么呢 停下
Hey, bro, what are you doing? Stop that!
有人在这儿搞事情
He's doing something in here!
来人 快来人 有人在捣鬼
Guards! Guards! He's doing something!
闭嘴 是我先发现他的
No, you are not going to take credit for this.
你别想抢我的功劳
I am the one that saw it first.
滚一边儿去 芭比
Oh, take a hike, Barbie!
功劳都是我的 芭比
I'm getting the credit for it! Barbie?
没错 警卫 他俩会害死我们
These two are gonna get us killed!
天爪小队 天爪小队
Guards! Guards!
看这边 警卫
Raptors! Raptors! In here! Guards! Guards!
你们最好过来看看哦
I'm seeing something that you'd all wanna see!
乔伊
Joey!
交给你了
You have to take him.
我变形的时候没法带他
I can't carry him when I change forms.
不 小氪 小氪
Whoa, whoa, whoa. No, no, no! Krypto! Krypto!
别 小氪 别闹了
Stop! Krypto! Krypto! Stop!
会把宝宝压坏的 走开
You're gonna squash the baby. Stop!
看到什么了 找到他了吗
What do you see? Did you find him?
天哪 什么情况
Oh, my God! What is that?
传送门已经打开了太久
Portal's been open too long.
我们不能待在这儿了
We can't stand here much longer.
你脸色更难看了
Aw, you look like shit.
我没事
I'm fine.
口袋宇宙的传送门应该在那边
I think we need to get to those portals up there.
是吗 传送门
Uh, right. How do we...
怎么打开
...work them?
不知道 总会有办法
I don't know, but we'll figure it out.
好
Yeah.
乔伊
Joey!
他还很虚弱 干掉他
Kill him! He's still weak!
行了 怪物 给我乖乖地 回笼子里去
All right, freak. Nice and slow. Back in the cage.
你要干什么 泼水玩儿吗
What are you gonna do, splash us?
对 我要用氟锑酸泼你们
Yes. With fluoroantimonic acid.
好疼 疼死了
找到他了吗
Do you have him?
真是见鬼了 怎么了
Hot damn. What?
有只狗在飞
It's a flying dog.
噢 什么
Uh-oh. What?
来 过来
Come on, come on!
不 不 不
No, no, no! No!
黑洞
Black hole!
糟了
Oh, boy!
小氪 快过来 我出不去了
Krypto! Come here, boy! I can't get out of this!
小氪
Krypto!
前面是黑洞 我们困在这里了
It's a black hole! We'll never get out of it!
带我们出去
Pull us out!
小氪 过来 快过来
Krypto! Come!
别闹了 小氪 帮帮我们
Stop it! Krypto! Help us out!
坏狗狗
Bad boy!
雷克斯
Rex!
乔伊
Joey!
兄弟 你可真奇怪
Man, you are so weird.
有发现了吗 很多
Do you have him? Them.
超人 穿披风的狗 小宝宝 还有个拖把一样的人
Superman, a mean dog in a cape, a weird baby, and a squiggle man.
什么
What?
卓越 跟我来
Terrific? Follow me!
小氪 停下 别闹了
Krypto! No! Leave it!
你这条臭狗
Are you kidding me?
那个很贵的
Those things aren't cheap!
我的天哪 谢谢你
Oh, my gosh. Thank you.
宝贝
Hey, buddy.
嘿
Hey. Hey.
你来救我了 对
You came to get me. Yeah.
还有很多人 被关在那个地方
There's more people... being held prisoner in there.
得去救他们
We gotta go get 'em.
喔
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
现在可不能去 你状态太差了
Not through here, you can't. Not with you like this.
这怎么回事
Clark, what the--
中了氪石的毒
It's Kryptonite poisoning.
过一两天他就能恢复
He'll heal, but it'll take a day or two.
带他去安全的地方 坐我的飞行器走
Get him someplace safe. Take the T-craft.
操作很简单 很快就能掌握
The controls are easy and intuitive.
我留在这儿确保传送门不出问题
I need to stay back here and make sure the portal is secure.
好 好的
Okay... okay.
我看看
Okay.
好的
不行 小狗 你给我马上
No. Dog? Dog, I really need to--
下去 你赶快 下去
No. Dog, I really need you to--
听着
Come on.
算了 这很简单
Okay. Intuitive.
对 没什么
Yeah. For sure.
好 出来了
Okay. That's it.
哇哦
Whoa!
都捡起来
Pick that up!
伊芙 别拍了 滚出去
Eve! Get out of here, you idiot!
滚
Go!
快滚
Move!
他到底是怎么从那儿跑出去的
How the hell could he have gotten free? Hmm?
我必须要找到他
We need to find him.
伊芙
Eve?
我受够了 吉米
Oh, I'm so done, Jimmy.
呃
Oh, um...
我要把所有的料都给你 彻底毁了他
I have everything you need to ruin Lex forever.
什么 在哪儿
What? Where?
就在我手机里
Oh, I have it right here.
他居然敢朝我扔铅笔
How dare he throw a pencil at me?
服务器
等着瞧 我要让他后悔一辈子
He's gonna regret harming me for the rest of his life.
混蛋东西
Such a jerk.
我把这些都发给你
But if I send you this, Jimmy...
呃
Uh-huh.
可我有个条件 这周末你要出来见我
You have to promise me we get to hang this weekend.
我们去约会
Just the two of us.
呃
Uh...
好呀 真的吗 太好了
Okay. Yeah? Okay! Yay!
可以 要约会 多长时间
Uh-huh. How, uh... How long?
整个周末 整个周末
All weekend. All weekend?
那真是抱歉了
Oh, my God, Jimmy!
原来跟我约会给你造成这么大压力
I'm sorry this is such a major imposition on your life!
没有 约会没有压力的 我
No, it's not an imposition, I--
你根本不想去 我听出来了
I can tell you don't really think so.
不 不要这样 伊芙
No, no, no, no, no-- Eve?
发送
变异脚趾 卢瑟集团 图片
我真服了她了
Come on, Eve.
我叫玛莎 这是乔
I'm-- I'm Martha. This is Jon.
我是露易丝 露易丝
I'm Lois. Hi. Lois.
好了 儿子
Here, son.
妈妈
Hi, Ma.
妈妈 他们送我来是为了支配所有人
Ma, they sent me here to rule over everyone.
他们送我过来杀人
They sent me here to kill people.
克拉克 别说了 那不是
Clark, that ain't-- that ain't...
无敌蟹棒
你说 我儿子 他会好起来吗
Is our boy gonna be okay?
会的 卓越先生说他会好的
Yes. Mr. Terrific says yes.
你别理他 露易丝
Don't mind him, Lois.
他就是太爱担心
He's just a big ol' mush.
儿子受伤 他更爱瞎想了
Especially when it comes to Clark.
吉米·奥尔森 打给我
吉米·奥尔森 转发 卢瑟集团 图片
这个女生天天缠着你
This girl is obsessed with you?
呃
Uh-huh.
你怎么本事这么大 吉米
How do you do it, Jimmy?
我也不想来烦你
Look, I didn't even want to bother you,
可你说过有线索就联系你 所以
but you told me to call with anything I got, so I--
对 可她不是说一半就不出声了吗
Yeah, but I thought you said she disappeared off the line.
谁知道呢 可能是她手机掉马桶里了
I don't know. She might have dropped her phone in the toilet.
她经常掉手机
She does that a lot.
反正 我看不出来性感自拍能有什么
Well, I'm not really sure that sexy selfies are--
新博拉维亚 卢瑟里亚 贾汉普
你的火辣前女友是个天才
Your hot ex is a genius.
火辣吗 得联系佩里
Hot? We have to talk to Perry.
我马上就过去找你
I'll be there as soon as I can, okay?
背着莱克斯·卢瑟给别人发性感自拍
Sending sexy selfies behind the back of Lex Luthor?
她真是天字头一号大蠢货
She has to be the biggest idiot in the world.
莱克斯 他都说了 传送门已经被破坏了
Lex, he just told you, the portal was destroyed!
通向口袋宇宙的缝隙还在那儿
The dimensional aperture is still there...
等等 你来跟他说
Syd, tell him!
可以远程操作 赶紧打开
...which we can open remotely, so open it.
这样做 不安全
It is not... safe!
之后我们可以输入坐标 关闭时空缝隙 对不对
We can close the aperture later by inputting the coordinates, correct?
理论上是的 很好
Theoretically. Great!
既然找不到超人 就让他来找我们
If we can't find him, we'll need to draw him out.
传送门程序错误 保护功能失效
莱克斯 你这样做可能会让我们周围的世界 出现时空裂缝
But Lex, that could tear a dimensional rift into the surrounding area!
这么做的风险 我很清楚
This is something you think I don't know?
情况有点不太对 你这会儿明白了
That shouldn't happen. Oh, you don't say!
拜托 你能阻止它吗 你问我吗
Can you... Can you stop it? Can I stop it?
看到了吗 制造口袋宇宙 就是这个后果
This is why you don't create a damn pocket universe.
警告 打开了 这下超人一定会赶过来
There. Superman won't be able to ignore that.
我们就能掌握他的位置了
Now we know where he'll be next.
我一猜你就在这里
Thought you was out here.
老爸
Hey, Pa.
第一次看到你睡那么久
Never seen you sleep that long.
上礼拜 我 你妈 还有赫克托他们
Last week me, Ma, Hector and them,
我们一起开车去吃墨西哥卷饼
we took a drive to Beerki's Burritos
在勒泰斯那边
down in Luttus.
过去在高速路边上 蓝色谷仓外面
Like the one that used to be out by that old, uh, blue barn,
也有一家卷饼 记得吗
out on that I-9, you remember that?
那家卷饼 永远是那么香
Mm-hmm. Burritos still just as good.
那个露安娜 挺不错的姑娘
That Louanne, she-- she seems nice.
是露易丝
It's Lois. Hmm?
她叫露易丝
Her name's Lois.
她确实挺好的
But yeah, she's... she's nice.
你是不是状态不太好
But you don't seem quite yourself.
我亲生父母发的那条信息
Yeah, well, that message that my parents sent with me,
我是第一次听到后半部分
I had never heard the second half before.
要我说 你之前对那段录像的理解
Well, I'd say what you wanted that message to mean
已经说明了你是怎样的人
says a whole lot more about you
至于别人怎么想 都无所谓
than what anyone meant for it to mean.
老爸 你不明白
Pa, you don't understand.
我已经不知道自己是谁了
I'm not who I thought I was.
他们想让我去破坏
They sent me here to hurt people.
当父母的也没法告诉孩子 你应该是谁
Parents aren't for telling their children who they're supposed to be.
我们只能尽量 提供帮助
We are here to give y'aII tools,
让你自己犯错 自己成长
help you make fools of yourselves all on your own.
不
No.
是你的选择 克拉克
Your choices, Clark.
和你的行动
Your actions.
真正决定了 你是谁
That's what makes you who you are.
我还要对你说
I'll tell you something, son.
我从心底
I couldn't be...
为你感到骄傲
...more proud of you.
这老头子
Ol' mush.
克拉克 你最好来看一下电视
Clark, there's something on the box you might wanna see.
来看东欧局势
And over in Eastern Europe,
博拉维亚军队在两国边境集结
Boravian troops gather at the border,
突发新闻 博拉维亚军队在边境集结
似乎很快要对贾汉普发起第二次进攻
seemingly mere minutes away from invading Jarhanpur once again.
附近的村民表示 他们愿意全力守卫自己的国家
Now, nearby villagers are willing and ready to defend their country,
虽然博拉维亚的军队训练有素
despite the exponentially superior firepower
突发新闻 博拉维亚军队在边境集结
在火力上拥有压倒性优势
of the well-trained Boravian military.
这些村民已经被博拉维亚军队包围
The villagers cling onto what little hope they have left,
但他们依然心存希望
as they're surrounded by the military.
突发新闻 博拉维亚军队在边境集结
博拉维亚总统瓦西尔·古尔科斯表示
Boravian president, Vasil Ghurkos, says the invasion
这次军事行动是为了帮助贾汉普人民 推翻独裁政府
is to protect the Jarhanpurian people from a tyrannical government.
超人 超人
Superman! Superman!
超人 超人 超人
Superman! Superman! Superman!
超人 超人
Superman! Superman!
这次 没有超人出来力挽狂澜
Without Superman here to stop it this time,
恐怕贾汉普 无法避免战火
the Jarhanpurians don't have much hope.
我帮你把鞋刷了 我去拿过来
I cleaned your boots. I'll go get 'em for you.
超人
Superman.
我们需要你来大都会 马上
We need you here in Metropolis now.
可我要先去博拉维亚
I have to get to Boravia, Terrific.
要是你不来 博拉维亚 大都会和地球都要完了
There won't be a Boravia, or a Metropolis, or a Planet Earth, if you don't get here soon.
时空裂缝在接近城市
This rift is about to tear into the city.
我没法阻止它 我需要你的帮助
I can't stop it. I need your help.
大都会市民请注意
All Metropolis citizens.
请马上撤离 不要逗留
This is a mandatory evacuation.
重复一遍 现在强制执行撤离命令
Repeat: this evacuation is not optional.
请马上撤离 不要逗留
This is a mandatory evacuation.
重复一遍 请马上撤离 不要逗留
Repeat: this evacuation is not optional.
现在强制执行撤离命令
This is a mandatory evacuation.
哥谭市 靠左行驶 昆士兰公园 靠右行驶
对 它肯定害怕 去找它
Yeah, I'm sure she's scared, but find her.
我们大家都害怕
Yeah, we're all equally scared.
拜托 让它接电话
Come on, just put her on.
胡安妮塔 让珀耳塞福涅接电话
Please, Juanita, can you put Persephone on the phone?
算我求你了 让我听听猫猫的声音
Yes, she will care! Cats know the sound of your voice!
我想办法联系了博达银行的线人
So, I was able to connect with our contact at BodaBank.
卢瑟集团一直在以极低的价格 对博拉维亚出售武器
Luthor's been selling arms to Ghurkos for pennies on the dollar for years.
你就不好奇吗 我的确好奇
Why, you ask? I do ask why.
如果贾汉普被攻占 他能得到一半的国土
He did it in exchange for half of Jarhanpur.
开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
一开始 我还以为伊芙只是在发自拍
At first, I thought Eve was just sending me selfies.
但你看 在背景里拍到了地图 合同
But in the background of the shots are maps, contracts,
贾汉普 新博拉维亚 卢瑟里亚
博拉维亚和莱克斯·卢瑟达成了协议
莱克斯·卢瑟 卢瑟集团首席执行官
all kinds of documents chronicling Boravia's agreement
美国特拉华州大都会 为对贾汉普的军事行动
提供军事支援与武器
占领贾汉普之后 一半国土归他所有
to cede half of the country to Lex Luthor once the invasion is complete.
莱克斯·卢瑟想当国王
He wants to make himself king.
国王吗 没错
King? King.
我们是不是该做些什么
Should we really still be standing here?
露易丝 那个飞行器还在屋顶上吗
Lois, you got that flying saucer deal up on the roof?
在 格兰特 特鲁普 我在
Yup. Grant. Troupe. Yup.
出发 白板也带上
Come on. Grab the board, Jimmy.
能坐几个人 五六个吧 六个
How many does it hold? Five, or six. Six.
好 隆巴德 你也来 谢谢
Okay. Lombard, you too. Oh, thank you.
莱克斯要一半沙漠有什么用
Why the hell would Lex want half a desert?
据他的狂热粉丝说 他会建立一个高科技乌托邦
His cultish acolytes believe he's gonna create a technologically advanced utopia.
乌托邦
Utopia?
同时也是摇钱树
There's a profit factor as well.
那边有大量的石油资源 足以让他赚个盆满钵满
I mean, the petroleum deposits alone are worth multiples of his investment.
无论动机是什么
Whatever his motives are,
莱克斯是千方百计想毁掉超人的名声
we know Luthor did everything he could to ruin Superman's reputation.
伊芙的照片可以证明 他就是博拉维亚之锤的幕后操纵者
Eve's photos show he was behind the whole Hammer of Boravia scam.
网上那些反对超人的评论 是他的水军发的
And all the bots stirring up anti-Superman sentiment online.
卓越先生说 那边正在扩张的时空裂缝 也是他造成的
Mr. Terrific believes Luthor is also behind the spreading rift between universes out there.
总之 他想让超人身败名裂
All of it seems to be geared toward stopping Superman
没法再阻止博拉维亚的侵略 老大
from standing in the way of the Boravian invasion, Chief.
叫我佩里就行 安排发稿 尽快
Call me Perry, kid. Post the story. Fast.
系好安全带 为什么我没座
Buckle up, kids. Why don't I have a seat?
吉米 你来记录好吗 好
Jimmy, will you transcribe? Uh-huh.
我的妈呀
Oh, God!
《星球日报》已获取独家资料
The Daily Planet has obtained exclusive information
公平竞争
可以证明亿万富翁莱克斯·卢瑟
proving that billionaire Lex Luthor is in league
和博拉维亚总统古尔科斯暗中勾结
with Boravian dictator, Vasil Ghurkos.
克拉克 你快到了吗
Clark, are you close?
裂缝离大都会越来越近了 我用代码也没法关闭它
It's about to hit Metropolis, and my codes are not shutting it down.
见鬼
Shit!
呃
Uh-oh.
莱克斯 裂缝就要过来了
Lex! The rift is almost here!
那就让它减速
So slow it down.
不行 只能输入代码让它停下
I can't unless I can put the code in to stop it.
那就再等一会儿
Hold on a minute then.
我们得离开这儿 奥提斯
We gotta go, man! Otis!
世界都要完蛋了 该降落在哪儿呢
Not sure where we're gonna land when the world is gone.
有个代码能关闭裂缝 但太复杂了 无法破解
There's a code to close the rift, but it's too complicated to hack.
代码肯定就在卢瑟集团里
Luthor will have the code at LuthorCorp.
稍等一下 我去带上小氪 然后
Just give me a minute. I'll get Krypto, and we'll go--
你还带了那条狗
You brought that dog, man?
对 不然 我们家养的牛 都被它咬死了
Yeah, I didn't-- didn't want him killing my parents' cows.
大都会流星队
切广角
Go on wide.
不对 切到工程师
Wrong. Focus on The Engineer.
我在跟超人 7R
I'm on the alien, Larry. 7R.
你们两个 现在回头还不晚
It's not too late for either of you.
5A
5A!
你们不用听从卢瑟的
You don't have to do what Luthor--
2X
2X!
安吉拉 按计划进行 灌满他的肺 杀了这个混蛋
Now, Angela, as planned, fill his lungs and kill the son of a bitch.
他不是可以憋气一个多小时吗
Can't he hold his breath for over an hour?
他的肺里没有空气了
Not without air in his lungs.
几分钟就会死
He'll be dead in minutes.
纳米机器人正在封锁他的视神经
The nanites are suppressing his optic nerve.
让他没法透视和看东西 肺部会破裂
Sight and X-ray vision should be completely muted. Lungs breached.
博拉维亚共和国
（博拉维亚语）喂
Da?
（博拉维亚语）可以发布了
我们不会入睡
[in Boravian] We will not sleep
除非每一条街道上
until the street is flooded
都洒满了贾汉普人的血
with the blood of every Jarhanpurian!
他在搞什么鬼
What's his game?
他想用摩擦力把机器人甩掉
Using friction to get the nanites off?
就算脸上的掉了也没用
Doesn't matter if he gets them off his face.
纳米机器人在他的肺里
The nanites are still in his lungs.
工程师 超霸 追上他
Engineer, Ultraman, keep up.
我们在追
We're trying.
别跟丢了他 知道 你别废话了
Maintain LOS. Yes. No shit, Larry.
快点儿
Hurry.
他很快就会窒息
He'll suffocate any minute.
工程师 彻底包住他
Engineer, envelop him completely.
等等 他在搞什么
Wait! Wait, wait! What is he doing?
速度太快了 如果冲到地面我会承受不住
I won't be able to sustain the impact at this speed.
不 安吉拉 收回纳米机器人 不然你们会摔死
No, Angela, unsheathe! He's the only one protected!
正在进入撞击洞口 切换红外镜头
Entering the hole. Infrared, please?
启动夜视仪
Switch to night vision.
哇
Whoa.
她还有心跳 但失去意识了
Her heart's still beating, but she's unconscious.
派兵支援
Call in the Raptors.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
没想到吧 克隆你其实很简单
That's right. Cloning you was relatively simple.
只要在你战斗过的地方
All it took was combing the aftermath of your battles...
收集你留下来的毛发就行了
...until I located a strand of your hair.
怪不得你能进入堡垒
That's how you got into the Fortress.
你有我的基因
You had my DNA.
没错 不过大部分情况下 克隆都会存在一些缺陷
Yes, but as is often the case with cloning, the match was imperfect.
这个克隆体比你本人还蠢 虽然你就是个蠢货
He might be even stupider than you. If that's possible.
不过他比你听话多了
But easier to control.
3L 也比你强多了
3L. And stronger.
22K
22K!
31D
31D!
2A
2A!
5B 5B
5B! 5B!
6K 9A
6K! 9A!
凭我的大脑一定能打败你
My brain will always win!
智慧胜过蛮力
Brain beats brawn!
超人 超人
Superman. Superman.
卢瑟 你在白费力气
No matter what you do to me, Luthor,
你不可能占领贾汉普
your plans in Boravia won't work.
真的吗 为什么
Oh, really? Why's that?
因为我朋友去帮忙了
'Cause I called in some friends.
卢瑟先生
Mr. Luthor?
边境的情况不太妙
There is an anomaly at the border.
贾汉普 博拉维亚
抱歉 孩子
Sorry, kid.
超人来不了了
Superman couldn't make it.
但我们更厉害
So you got an upgrade.
我们的军队对付不了超人类
[in Boravian] Our forces aren't prepared to deal with metahuman anomalies.
我下令叫他们撤退了
I've sent the word to retreat.
撤退
Retreat?!
不 不 不
No! No! No!
我们得赶紧躲进掩体里
We must get to the bunker!
掩体
The bunker!
我知道你不敢杀我
I know you won't kill me.
你太软弱 不会使用暴力 就像超人一样
You are too delicate and weak, like Superman.
我和超人可不一样
I'm not like Superman.
完美 立即发布 好的
It's perfect. Post it, kid. On it.
复制准备就绪 亿万富翁莱克斯·卢瑟串通外国势力
网页端准备就绪 亿万富翁莱克斯·卢瑟串通外国势力
发布 亿万富翁莱克斯·卢瑟串通外国势力
超人 你搞错了 我的目标并不是侵略贾汉普
I think you overestimate the importance of Jarhanpur to me, Superman.
那只是额外奖励
That was just a bonus.
我之所以杀你 并不是为了让博拉维亚入侵贾汉普
I'm not killing you so the Boravian military conflict can proceed.
相反 我怂恿博拉维亚进攻贾汉普
I created the Boravian military conflict
是为了找到借口 杀掉你
so I'd have an excuse to kill you!
一旦你介入国际纷争
Once you involved yourself,
美国政府肯定会支持我干掉你
I knew I could easily get our government's support in nullifying you.
为什么
Why?
因为你会毁了我们
Because you're destroying us!
10Y 13B
10Y. 13B.
卢瑟 你是在嫉妒我
You're driven by envy, Luthor.
是个人都看得出来 还用你说 我早就知道
You couldn't be more obvious. No shit. I'm not dim.
我很清楚 我的内心燃烧着嫉妒之火
I'm aware envy consumes my every waking moment.
13L
13L.
别人总把我比作伽利略 爱因斯坦
I know when they mention Galileo or Einstein
这些蠢材哪配和我相提并论
or one of these other twits in the same breath as me,
我听到这些夸奖 恶心得快要吐了
I feel a tide of vomit burn the back of my throat.
但至少伽利略有所作为
But at least Galileo did something.
不像你这个蠢货 从金星跑到地球
He wasn't some dopey Venusian catapulted onto this planet,
轻轻松松就让所有人赞美你 崇拜你
just to have the world fawn over him,
因为你的力量 让我们意识到 自己是多么弱小
because his strength illuminates how weak we all really are.
我对你的嫉妒 就是我的动力
So, my envy is a calling.
也是人类的希望
It is the sole hope for humanity,
因为我已经看清 为了全世界的未来 必须除掉你这个毒瘤
because it is what has driven me to annihilating you.
1A
1A!
1A 1A
1A! 1A!
1A
1A! 1A! 1A! 1A!
好极了
Yes.
你还在笑什么 你这个白痴
Oh, what are you smirking at, you idiot?
智慧胜过蛮力
Brain beats brawn.
抱歉 兄弟
Sorry, chum.
宠物用品店
不 快阻止它
No, no, no! No!
你就是靠这些无人机 给他发指令 对吗
You watch him through those? Tell him what to do?
小氪
Krypto.
那边有玩具
Get the toy.
三 三十 这只死狗
Uh, thir-thirty-s-- Oh, the stupid dog!
无信号
三号机损坏
Uh... Charlie down!
12C 四号机损坏
12C! Aah! Delta down.
36B
36B--
不 这台也坏了
No. Hotel down!
无信号
不 二号机损坏
No! Bravo down.
二号机损坏 我刚说了 你又抢我的话
Bravo down! I just said that, Larry!
无信号
一号机损坏
Alpha down!
莱克斯
Lex.
天爪小队到了
The Raptors have arrived.
杀了他 有本事就来吧
Kill him! Good luck with that.
嘿
Hey!
这都什么时候了 你还在那儿偷懒
This ain't playtime! Quit messin' around!
要赶快找到卢瑟 关闭时空裂缝
We have to get to Luthor to stop the rift.
我没有偷懒
I'm not messing around.
我在干正事儿
I'm doing important stuff.
裂缝就快要到贝克林区了
It's gonna reach Bakerline any minute.
那里有很多居民
There are people there.
我们赶紧逃吧 根本逃不掉了
We have to go. We'll never make it in time.
好了 快跑吧
It's almost here. We have to try. Come on.
莱克斯
Lex!
我现在就关闭裂缝
I'm closing the freakin' rift.
不行 他们支持超人 死了也是活该
No! They chose him! Let them die!
我们先躲躲 什么
We'll close it from the bunker... What?
只要我喜欢的城市没裂开就行
...before it gets to a city I care about.
打开传送门
Open the portal!
收拾一下 准备离开
Wrap it up. Let's go.
大家都注意安全
Safety first, people.
我有关闭裂缝的代码
Hey. Hey. The code to close the rift is in here.
我能帮忙 用不着
I can help. I don't need your help.
我可是无敌的卓越先生
I'm goddamn Mr. Terrific.
可恶 去死吧 外星人
You piece of shit alien!
你错了 这就是你对我最大的误解 莱克斯
That is where you've always been wrong about me, Lex.
我和你们一样都是人
I'm as human as anyone.
我会爱 也会害怕
I love, I... I get scared.
我每天早上起来 都要面对许多未知
I wake up every morning, and despite not knowing what to do,
但我还是努力生活
I put one foot in front of the other,
尽己所能做出正确的选择
and I try to make the best choices I can.
我经常犯错
I screw up all the time.
但人类的天性就是会犯错
But that is being human.
不怕犯错才是我的力量
And that's my greatest strength.
我衷心希望 有一天你也能明白
And someday I hope, for the sake of the world,
真正的力量到底来自哪里
you understand that it's yours too.
真会说
Oh, that's beautiful.
我劝你还是省省吧 你这个自视甚高的小丑
But none of this matters, you patronizing clown.
政府已经授权给我 让我杀了你
The government gave me the authority to kill you.
哪怕今天不行 明天我也
If not today, then tomor--
啊
Ahh!
别
No, no, no!
天啊 快停下 好了 小氪 快停下
Oh, my-- Stop. Krypto, put him down.
小氪 别闹了
Krypto, drop him!
快把他放下来 听话
Krypto, drop him! Drop him!
服了
Dude.
搞定
Got it.
太好了
Yes!
嗯
Mmm.
莱克斯 干什么
Lex. What?
《星球日报》刚刚发布了 一条震惊全国的新闻
Well, this just in. An absolute bombshell from the Daily Planet.
亿万富翁莱克斯·卢瑟 一直在暗中勾结外国势力
Billionaire Lex Luthor aligning himself with a foreign entity, believe it or not.
头条新闻 莱克斯·卢瑟是叛国贼吗
向博拉维亚无偿提供 价值几百亿的武器
Luthor has been giving them billions and billions of dollars' worth of free weapons--
莱克斯·卢瑟一直与
Lex Luthor has been working covertly
博拉维亚的瓦西尔·古尔科斯暗中合作
with Vasil Ghurkos and the Boravian government
重大新闻 莱克斯·卢瑟是叛国贼吗
企图侵略独立国家贾汉普
to overthrow the country of Jarhanpur.
卢瑟免费提供了
Luthor has been giving them billions...
卢瑟曾经多次来我们节目当嘉宾
We've had Luthor on this show many times.
莱克斯·卢瑟 叛国贼
但没想到他是个叛国贼 一直妄想着能当国王
Little did we know, he was a traitor.
说得对
保守派和自由派的意见终于统一了
Seems like the one thing conservatives and liberals can finally agree on
大都会 马克斯维尔·劳德发表看法
都同意莱克斯·卢瑟是个混蛋
is that Lex Luthor sucks.
他散布假消息 让民众都与超人为敌
The whole world has turned against Superman,
事到如今 我们都该向超人道歉
and we all owe him an enormous apology.
星球日报揭露卢瑟的恐怖计划
他从没说过谎 一直是大家心中的英雄
He is, of course, the hero we always thought he was.
谢谢你 谢谢
Thank you! Thank you!
你真厉害
That was sick.
盖 不如让他加入我们吧
Guy, maybe he should join the group.
别闹了
Please.
我不是要针对你 但你长得太吓人了
I mean, no offense, but that creepy mug is what you want
和正义帮形象不符
representing the Justice Gang?
正义帮
Justice Gang?
好酷的名字
That's a cool name.
欢迎加入
You're in.
来吧
Come on!
你愿意信任超人类就好 瑞克
Glad you're not concerned about the metahumans, Rick.
以后可就是他们的天下了
'Cause now they're the ones making the rules.
此次事件将产生怎样的国际影响
又会如何震荡美国和博拉维亚的关系
目前还是未知
请注意秩序 往前走
Everyone file. This way, please.
慢点儿
Easy!
弗勒莱特 妈妈
Fleurette! Mom!
噢
Oh!
送他去美梦监狱
Get his bald ass to Belle Reve.
遵命
噢
Oh!
这下我们可以永远在一起了
Now we can be together forever.
莱恩小姐
Miss Lane.
你好
Oh, hi.
我想要接受你的采访
I thought I might give you an interview.
我能告诉你这次事件的所有内幕
I could fill you in on all of the behind-the-scenes.
好啊
Sure.
我很愿意
I think that would be...
采访你
great.
呃
Um...
我们去那边吧
How about over here?
方便采访
For an interview.
嘿
Hey.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
莱西商店街
他俩好了多久了
How long have they been hooking up?
三个多月吧
About three months, I think.
真正的英雄
大都会永远铭记 马里炸豆丸子的摊主马里
你们收拾得真干净
Got this place cleaned up pretty good.
把自己也收拾得不错
Cleaned yourself up pretty good, too.
真的吗 真的
You think so? Yeah.
看着很有个性
Think it gives you character.
您能给我起个名字吗
Maybe one day you'll give me a name.
可是 你叫四号啊
Well. Four's a name.
不能叫加里吗
So is Gary.
真烦
Aw, shoot.
先生 您的表妹回来了
Sir, I think your cousin has returned.
是啊 大哥 你搞什么鬼
Yup. What the hell, dude?
你怎么把门给拆了
Why did you move the door?
门一直在那儿啊 对了 我的狗呢
I didn't move the door. Where is my dog?
好吧 怪不得小氪总是不听我的话
Okay, well, this is why he has behavioral issues.
太胡闹了
No boundaries.
这样真不健康
It's not healthy, is it? Mm-mmm.
走吧
Come on.
谢谢你帮忙看狗 二货
Thanks for watching him, bitch.
她刚从红色太阳的星系回来
She likes to go and party on other planets.
又去喝酒了
Planets with red suns. Oh.
因为 在太阳系的行星上 我们是喝不醉的
Because of our metabolism, we can't get drunk on a planet with a yellow sun.
如果我拥有情感功能 我肯定会担心她的身体健康
If I had any emotional capacity whatsoever, I'd be concerned about her partying.
是啊
Yeah.
超人 您想看看自己父母的录像吗
Superman, would you like to see the footage of your parents?
这段录像能安慰他
He finds it soothing. Oh!
好啊 加里 放吧
Yeah, Gary, that'd be nice.
厌倦了光鲜外表
♪ I'm driving to my star ♪
这是你第一次看到这个世界
Everything you see, you're seeing for the first time.
我所畏惧地听着音乐
♪ I'm listening to the music With no fear ♪
这些都是给你的
All of this is for you.
若你真诚也能听见
♪ You can hear it too If you're sincere ♪
克拉克
Clark.
因为我就是朋克摇滚手
♪ 'Cause I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
我是个朋克摇滚手 没错就是我
♪ Well, I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
你做到了
You did it!
我是个朋克摇滚手 没错就是我
♪ 'Cause I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
♪ Well, I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
导演 编剧 詹姆斯·古恩
看你在大街上踉踉跄跄
♪ I see you stagger In the street ♪
制片人 皮特·萨夫兰 詹姆斯·古恩
连站都站不稳
♪ And you can't stay On your feet ♪
执行制片人 尚塔尔·农沃 拉斯·温特
执行制片人 尼古拉斯·科尔达
连睡觉都在装模作样
♪ And you're faking In your sleep ♪
执行制片人 皮特·基亚佩塔
安德鲁·拉里 安东尼·提塔尼格罗
故事基于DC漫画角色创作
多希望自己很在行
♪ You wish that you were deep ♪
"超人"超人角色创作 杰里·西格尔 及 乔·舒斯特
摄影指导 亨利·布拉罕
你无法听见我独自狂笑
♪ But you can't hear me Laughing to myself ♪
艺术指导 贝丝·米克尔
若可以 你早想成为别人
♪ If you could You would be someone else ♪
剪辑 威廉·霍伊
克雷格·阿尔珀特
音乐 约翰·墨菲 大卫·弗莱明
因为我就是朋克摇滚手
♪ 'Cause I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
视效总监 斯蒂芬妮·切雷蒂
视效制片人 苏珊·皮克特
我是个朋克摇滚手 没错就是我
♪ Well, I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
服装设计 朱迪安娜·马科夫斯基
选角 约翰·帕普西德拉
因为我就是朋克摇滚手
♪ 'Cause I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
主演 大卫·科伦斯韦
瑞秋·布罗斯纳安
我是个朋克摇滚手 没错就是我
♪ Well, I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
尼古拉斯·霍尔特
埃迪·盖瑟吉
安东尼·卡里根
看我倒在布利克街
♪ See me die On Bleecker Street ♪
内森·菲利安
伊莎贝拉·莫塞德
厌倦了扮演上帝
♪ I'm bored with being God ♪
斯凯勒·吉桑多 萨拉·桑帕约
玛利亚·加布里埃拉·法里亚
看我驾驶飞驰在路上
♪ See me steering in my car ♪
维德尔·皮尔斯 艾伦·图代克
普路特·泰勒·文斯 内娃·豪威尔
向着我的星辰驶去
♪ I'm driving to my star ♪
美国DC影业
无所畏惧地听着音乐
♪ I'm listening to the music With no fear ♪
美国领域电影制作公司 联合出品
美国巨魔法庭娱乐
若你真诚也能听见
♪ You can hear it too If you're sincere ♪
美国萨夫兰公司 制作
詹姆斯·古恩 导演作品
因为我就是朋克摇滚手
♪ 'Cause I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
《超人》
我是个朋克摇滚手 没错就是我
♪ Well, I'm a punk rocker Yes, I am ♪
一 二 三 四
One, two, three, four!
进口 中国电影集团公司
联合发行 中国电影股份有限公司
华夏电影发行有限责任公司
译制 长影集团译制片制作有限责任公司
我们拥有自己的星球 用那些被我们击倒的残骸铸就
♪ We're on a planet of our own That we made from the bones ♪
译制职员
那些被我们KO的家伙
♪ Of the ones that we KO'd ♪
翻译 涅伽达 许诺 徐子怡
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
字幕 袁野
要为质疑的猎物 提前掘好坟墓
♪ Gonna dig an early grave For the daughters ♪
那些压抑的日子已经结束
♪ And deprave them With those depressing days ♪
制片主任 丁忠伟
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
制片 都业枫 李宏媛
我们不会再忍受 绝不会再屈服
♪ Ain't gonna take this Ain't gonna take this ♪
我是新反抗军的异类
♪ I am a hellion The new rebellion ♪
喊出我们的名字 大声喊出来
♪ Say our name, boy Just say our name, boy ♪
我们是无敌蟹之乐
♪ It's the Mighty Crabjoys ♪
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
我知道你说这不会长久
♪ I know you said This wouldn't last ♪
那些只是过去的陈词滥调
♪ That's a voice That's from your past ♪
我不听那些鼠辈的闲言碎语
♪ I don't listen To those rats ♪
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
母亲总说我是个痴人
♪ My mother says That I'm a fool ♪
父亲训诫要循规蹈矩
♪ Dad says Obey the rules ♪
他们看不见这颗璀璨明珠
♪ They can't see This stunning jewel ♪
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
我们决不妥协
♪ Not gonna take this ♪
绝不屈服
♪ We will not take this ♪
我们是新反抗军的异类
♪ We are the hellions The new rebellions ♪
曾经是你的世界 现在由我们主宰
♪ It was your world, boy Now it's our world, boy ♪
我们是无敌蟹之欢
♪ We are the Mighty Crabjoys ♪
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
我们是无敌蟹之欢
♪ We are the Mighty Crabjoys ♪
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
我们是无敌蟹之欢
♪ We are the Mighty Crabjoys ♪
噢
♪ Oi oi oi ♪
我们是无敌蟹
♪ We are the Mighty ♪
喔
Whoo!
之欢
♪ Crabjoys ♪
那个
Hmm.
什么
What?
怎么了
Yeah?
有点儿 没对上
It's just... a little off.
你想怎么样
What do you want me to do?
难道让我拆了 重新拼一遍
Do you want me to take it apart and put it back together?
不 我就是
No, no, no, no. I was just...
就是怎么样
You just what?
对不住 哥们儿 我没想惹你生气
Hey, man. I'm sorry. I didn't mean to bum you out.
就当我没说
I shouldn't have brought it up.
没想到 有时候我也挺坏的
Darn it, I can be such a jerk sometimes.